(
"ai_sub_version": "3.6.0",
"generated_at": "2026-10-05T13:27:07.905681",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"service_tier": null,
"service_tier_subtitles": null,
"service_tier_lyrics": null,
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
のじゃーー！
Nojaaa!
あららら、めらめら、あちちめらー！
Ararara, meramera, Achichi Mela!
ホロライブ遊び隊！こりゃく担当の、ヒケシヤサランダー！
Hololive Asobi-tai! Strategy lead, Hikeshia Salamander!
あちちめらののじゃー！
Achichi Mela's Noja!
こんばんは。のじゃこんばんはー。
Good evening. Noja good evening.
のじゃこんばんはー。
Noja good evening.
今日はね、妹にね、運転を教えてあげようと思うんじゃが、
Today, I thought I'd teach my little sister how to drive,
今大流行の、妹に運転を教えるゲームがあるらしいんじゃが、
and apparently there's a super popular game about teaching your sister how to drive,
一旦わしの運転について教えちゃう。うん。
so I'll teach you about my own driving first. Yeah.
わしね、免許持ってない。
You see, I don't have a driver's license.
免許取ろうとしたこともないのじゃ。免許持ってない。
I've never even tried to get one. I don't have a license.
免許持ってないから、あの、正直めちゃ不安なのじゃ。
So, to be honest, I'm super nervous about this.
不安、不安だし、あの、お主ら悪夢ってみることある？
I'm nervous, and... do you guys ever have nightmares?
わしよく悪夢を見るんじゃけど、あのね、あの、免許持ってないし、運転の仕方かんないのに、
I have nightmares a lot where, you know, I don't have a license and don't know how to drive,
あの車に乗せられて運転しなきゃいけない夢見るのじゃ、よく。そういうことない？
yet I get put in a car and have to drive. Ever happen to you?
そういうことない？分かるお主ら。
Doesn't that happen? You guys get it, right?
運転できない人分かる？この気持ち。
Can people who can't drive relate to this feeling?
え、わし運転できないのに、どうしようって思って、あの運転させられて、そのまま事故る夢をね、見る。
Like, 'I can't drive, what should I do?', and then I'm forced to drive and end up crashing.
そう、ブレーキが使えない、しかもブレーキどこにあるかもわかんないし、そういう怖いね夢をね、見る。
Yeah, I have scary dreams like that where the brakes don't work and I don't even know where they are.
え、無免許運転って炎上しちゃうよね。ゲーム内でも炎上しちゃう？
Wait, driving without a license would get me canceled. Does it get you canceled in games too?
怖いのだじゃ。火の用心じゃ。空飛べないのじゃ。
That's scary. Watch out for fire. I can't fly.
サランダーは空飛べないのじゃ。
Salamander can't fly.
うん。こわい。こわい。あと妹はいないのじゃ。
Yeah. It's scary. Scary. Also, I don't have a sister.
わし一人っ子だから、なんじゃろ、こう一人に何かを教えるってのが慣れてるかわかんなくて、
I'm an only child, so I'm not sure if I'm used to teaching someone something by myself,
ないけど…
"No, but..."
まあ、あの、きっとね、妹とかいたらすごい可愛いんだろうなって思うから
"Well, um, I'm sure if I had a younger sister,
she'd be super cute, so..."
可愛いんだろうなって思うから、すごい優しく
"I think she'd be super cute,
so I'll be super kind..."
優しく優しく教えてあげようと思うのじゃ。
"I'll teach her so, so kindly."
今日は架空の妹にね、架空の妹に教えてあげる。
"Today, I'll teach a fictional younger sister,
a fictional younger sister."
飛べないよサラマンダー、飛べないのじゃあ。
"Can't fly, Salamander,
you can't fly at all."
右手のレバー引いたらブレーキ？
"If I pull the lever on my right,
that's the brake?"
本当それ！わし信じちゃうよ！わし信じちゃうよ！
"Really? I'll actually believe that!
I'll actually believe that!"
でも免許取る予定とかもないから、あれなんじゃが、飛べないサラマンダー、ただのサラマンダー。
"But since I don't plan on getting a license anyway...
A salamander that can't fly is just a salamander."
え、わし飛べなくてもいい？わし飛べた方がいい？
"Eh, is it okay if I can't fly?
Is it better if I can fly?"
今日はメラオ姉ちゃんにね、なららせていただきますのじゃ。左がブレーキ、左がブレーキね。
"Today, I'll have Mela-oneechan teach me.
Left is the brake, left is the brake, right?"
うーん、教えるの上手い？よし、じゃあお主らの期待にこたえるべく
"Hmm, am I good at teaching?
Alright, then to meet everyone's expectations..."
頑張って教えようかな。なんかAIの妹っぽくて
"I'll do my best to teach.
It's kind of like an AI younger sister..."
AIの妹に、あの、口で、声で、あの、こうやるんだよってのを教えて、それを聞いてAIの妹が操作していくみたいなゲームっぽくて、うん。
"And you tell the AI younger sister with your mouth, with your voice,
'do it like this,' and she listens and operates it, kind of like that kind of game, yeah."
で、果たしてわしはこのさ、のじゃとかさ、言うじゃん、これが伝わるんじゃろうかみたいな、そういう不安がちょっとありつつ、
"And I wonder if things like 'noja'
will get across, I have a bit of anxiety about that..."
のじゃでも伝わるんじゃろうかって不安はありつつ、やっていこうと、思いますのじゃ。
"Even with 'noja,' will it get across?
With that worry, I'll go ahead and do it."
のじゃ。で、さっきごはんめちゃくちゃいっぱい食べたから
"Noja. And I ate a whole bunch
of rice earlier,"
お腹いっぱいなのじゃ。お腹パンパンなのじゃ。あの、豚バラ大根食べたのじゃ。
"so I'm full. My stomach is full.
Um, I ate pork belly and daikon radish."
食べ過ぎた。大根好きで食べ過ぎたのじゃ。
"I ate too much. I like daikon,
so I ate too much."
よし、頑張っていこうと思うのじゃ！おめめを外してゲームのお部屋に行くので、お主らその間に高評価をお願いしますのじゃ！よーいしょ！
"Alright, I'll do my best!
I'm taking off my mask and heading to the gaming room,
so everyone, please give a high rating in the meantime! Heave-ho!"
のじゃあ！
"Nojaa!"
来たよお兄ちゃん。なんでそんなに静かなの？ちょっと！呼び出しといて寝てるの？
"You came, Onii-chan. Why are you so quiet?
Hey! You called me out and you're sleeping?"
音量どうかなの？もっと大きい方がいい？これぐらいの方がいいかの？聞こえておるかの？
"How's the volume? Is louder better?
Is this about right? Can you hear me?"
妹がに運転を教えるんじゃけど、わしがお兄ちゃんね。スペースキーを押しながら話してください。
"My younger sister is going to teach me how to drive,
but I'm Onii-chan. Press and hold the space key while talking."
話すと妹が返事をします。ちょっとちっちゃい？よいしょ。これぐらいかな？
"When you speak, my younger sister replies.
A bit small? Heave-ho. Is this about right?"
なんでもいいので妹に話しかけてみましょう！話しかけるか。よし。えっとスペースキーを押して。あちち、めらんなのじゃ！どうじゃろ？
"Anything is fine, let's talk to my younger sister!
Shall I talk to her? Okay. Um, press the space key.
Hot, it's Mela-noja! How is it?"
お兄ちゃん、ノリで呼んだんなら起きてよ。私はまだ練習始めてないからね。
"Onii-chan, if you called me on a whim, wake up.
I haven't started practicing yet, you know."
免許あるのに、なんで教習受けなきゃいけないの？私、運転うまいんだけど？え？アクセルってどのペダル？そんなの踏んでれば分かるでしょ？
"Even though I have a license, why do I have to take lessons?
I'm good at driving, you know?
Eh? Which pedal is the accelerator?
You'll figure it out if you just step on it, right?"
なるほど？なんかなんし神経の妹っぽいのだ。なんか免許あるけどちょっと自信満々すぎて兄としてはやっぱ心配。兄としては心配っぽい。心配っぽいから教えてあげるっていうコンセプトなのかな？
"I see? It feels like a full-nerve younger sister.
She has a license, but she's way too confident,
so as an older brother, I'm worried.
Because she seems worried, the concept is to teach her, I guess?"
まぁじゃあ妹が今ほらハンドル握ってるのにシートベルト締めてないの危ないのだ。ちょっとこれはよくない。
"Well then, my younger sister, look,
is holding the steering wheel without wearing her seatbelt,
which is dangerous. This is not good."
シートベルトを締めるように言ってみましょう！
Let's tell her to fasten her seatbelt!
シートベルトを締めるのじゃ！
Fasten your seatbelt!
うん、はいはい。学園ノリで締めるよ。
Yeah, sure. I'll fasten it school-style.
あれ…これなんで動かないの？
Huh... Why isn't this moving?
エンジンをかけるように言ってみましょう！
Let's tell her to start the engine!
うんうん、シートベルトは締めたのじゃ。
Yeah, yeah, I fastened the seatbelt.
んで、エンジン……へえ、わしもね、わしもね、あの…何だっけ？
And the engine... Oh, me too, me too, um... what was it?
運転したことないから順番知らないんだけど、
I've never driven before so I don't know the order,
エンジンをかけるように言ってみましょう、了解。
Let's tell her to start the engine, got it.
妹ちゃん、エンジンをかけないと車は走らないのじゃ！
Little sis, the car won't run if you don't start the engine!
へへい、運転王子の説教タイムね。車がまだ眠そうなんで、エンジンはまだ焦らないでかけてみる。
Heh, driving prince's lecture time. The car still looks sleepy, so I'll try starting the engine without rushing.
なるほど。でもまあ無事にエンジンをかけれっぽい。
I see. But well, it looks like I successfully started the engine.
やっぱなんあのAI妹ちゃんところどころ何言ってるかかんないところあるけど、
As expected, AI little sis sometimes says things I don't quite understand, but...
うん。わし怒ってないのに怒ってって思われてるかも。
Yeah. She might think I'm angry even though I'm not.
でもなんかちょっとこれも気持ち分かる。お前らもない？
But somehow I kind of understand that feeling too. Don't you guys?
あの塾とかさ、学校とかさ、先生にさ勉強教えてもらう時さ、あの怒られてると感じたことない？
Like at cram school or school, when teachers are teaching you, haven't you ever felt like you were being scolded?
なんでこれ選んだのみたいな。それな気がしますのじゃ。
Like 'Why did you choose this?' I feel like that's it.
妹ちゃん、前にゆっくり進むのじゃ！
Little sis, move forward slowly!
わかった。じゃあ出発するね！
Got it. Then I'll set off!
おおおー、聞いたよ。じゃあ、にゅ…とゆっくり出るんだね。
Whoa, I hear you. So you move out slowly...
あんまり踏み込みすぎると止まるよ。
If you step on it too much, it'll stop.
おおー！おいおいおいおい！なになになになに！？
Whoa! Hey, hey, hey, hey! What's going on?!
ゆっくりって言ったのじゃ！
I said slowly!
ドライブコンプリートじゃねえよ！事故なのはじゃ！これでコンプリートならこの世界終わってるのじゃ！
This isn't a drive complete! It's an accident! If this is complete, this world is over!
え、わしの何が…わしの何がダメだったのじゃ？わし優しく教えたよね？のじゃ？次へ。
Eh, what was wrong with me... What was my mistake? I taught her gently, right? Right? Next.
S字コースをクリアしよう！
Let's clear the S-curve course!
シートベルトは締めてる。
Seatbelt is fastened.
え、エンジンかけた？うん、今エンジンはかけた！さあ、ちゃんと前見ておくよ。
Eh, did you start the engine? Yeah, I started the engine now! Now, I'll keep my eyes forward.
よし、あ、さっきチュートリアルで、あの強制？強制か、強制な感じね。了解。
Okay, ah, earlier in the tutorial, that forced? Forced, or a forced kind of vibe. Understood.
え、じゃあ、S字ね。どうしようかの。えっと、え、ちょ、ちょっとだけ前に進むのじゃ。ちょ、お兄ちゃん、スペースキーを離してくれないと聞こえないよ。
Eh, well, S-curve. What should I do? Um, eh, just, just move forward a little bit. Wait, big bro, you gotta let go of the spacebar or I can't hear you.
了解、ちょっとだけ前進ね！急かないから大丈夫、わたし悪い子じゃないよ。
Understood, just a little advance! No need to rush, it's fine, I'm not a bad girl.
お兄ちゃん、私と話すにはスペースキーを離さなきゃいけないって、わかってる…
Big bro, you know you have to release the spacebar to talk to me...
え、今のなに？私の運転、音だけで評価されてるみたいでちょっと笑っちゃうんだけど、ちゃんと言ってくれると助かる…。
Eh, what was that? It's kind of funny, like my driving is being evaluated just by sound, but it helps when you tell me clearly...
うわっ、左のまま走りたいんだね。ちょっとビビるけど、ちゃんとハンドル切るよ…あ、タイミングで左って本当に左？よく確認してね。
Whoa, you want to keep driving on the left. It's a bit scary, but I'll turn the steering wheel... Ah, is 'left' at this timing really left? Make sure to check well.
え、後ろ、後ろに、進むのじゃ。
Eh, back, move backward.
押しっぱなしじゃ聞こえないよ、スペースキーを離して。バックね、了解〜。お尻を下げるつもりでも、ちゃんと行こう。慎重にやるよ。
You won't hear me if you keep holding it, release the spacebar. Reversing, got it~. Even if we're lowering our rear, let's go properly. I'll do it carefully.
止まるのじゃ！お尻を下げる感じで、ちょっとだけ後ろに進むね、兄てね。
Stop! Lowering your rear, moving back just a little bit, big bro.
了解、止まるのじゃね。…あ、止まるって言うのは簡単だけど、心拍も止まりそうで焦る兄。早く言わなきゃ。決まった？よし、止まった。
Got it, you want to stop. ...Ah, saying stop is easy, but my heart rate is about to stop too, I'm panicking bro. I gotta say it quickly. Decided? Okay, stopped.
えーっと、えー、えーっと、うーん、ど、ど、なんて言うのがいいんじゃ？どうやったら教えられるんだろ？えっと、前に進んでちょっと左に進むのじゃ。
Um, um, um, how should I say it? How can I teach her? Um, move forward and move a little to the left.
お兄ちゃん、スペースキーを離してくれないと聞こえないよ。
Big bro, release the spacebar or I can't hear you.
うん、わかった〜ちょっと左前に進むね。これでいい？なんか方向転換って、頭で考えてくの早い気がする。
Yeah, I got it~ Moving forward and to the left a bit. Is this good? I feel like changing direction is something you think through quickly.
わかったよ！遅いの嫌だよね～。ちょっと減速してゆっくり行くね。兄、これで落…わかった、言い過ぎた感じでしょ？今のちょっと危ないかも…じゃあ位置と速度を落とすね。
Got it! You hate being slow, right~. I'll slow down a bit and go slowly. Bro, with this fa... Got it, that felt a bit like going too far, right? That might be a bit dangerous... Okay, I'll drop position and speed.
うん、一回落ち着こう。今は「位置と速度」って言われてるみたいだね、ちょっと…了解、ゆっくり後ろに進むのね。
Yeah, let's calm down once. It seems like we're being told 'position and speed', a bit... Got it, move backward slowly.
ちょっとだけ、ちょっとだけ、お尻が後ろへ…ふふ…ちゃんと見ててよ？ゆっくり右に進むのじゃ！
Just a little bit, just a little bit, rear goes backward... hehe... Are you watching properly? Move slowly to the right!
うん、見てるよ～。ゆっくり右に寄せて、ちゃんとついて来てね、兄、これでい…ゆっくりだよ、わかってる。
Yeah, I'm watching~. Pulling slowly to the right, make sure to follow along, bro, with this... It's slow, I know.
じゃあ余計にゆっくり行くね。上手に乗り心地も良くしてポイントまで待ってるよ。
Then I'll go extra slow. I'll make the ride smooth and wait until the point.
ゆっくり後ろに下がるのじゃ！お兄ちゃん、スペースキーを離してくれないと聞こえないよ。
Move backward slowly! Big bro, you need to release the spacebar or I can't hear you.
ゆっくり後ろに下がるね。私、ちょっとだけ動かすからどんといこい。あ、でもバランス気を付ける。兄の「見ててよ」って顔、ちゃんと見えるよ。
I'll move backward slowly. I'll move just a bit, so bring it on. Ah, but I'll mind my balance. I can clearly see your 'watch me' face, bro.
了解、止まるのじゃね。焦らないで止めたいよ～。今はどうだった？兄、ちゃんと審査し…
Got it, you want to stop. I want to stop without rushing~. How was it now? Bro, judge properly...
了解、止まるのじゃ。
Understood, I'm stopping.
焦らないで止めたよ〜。
I stopped without panicking~.
今はどうだった？
How was that?
ゆっくり前に進んで…ちょっと右なのだじゃ。
Move forward slowly... a bit to the right!
押しっぱなしじゃ聞こえないよ。
You can't hear if you hold it down.
スペースキーを離して。
Let go of the spacebar.
ちょっと右で前に進むね。
I'll move forward a bit to the right.
あ、兄、聞こえてる？
Ah, bro, can you hear me?
ハンドル握りながらだと声が遠いんだよね。
When you're holding the steering wheel, your voice sounds far away.
もう1回、はっきりお願い。
One more time, clearly please.
難しくないか？
Isn't it difficult?
速度、あ、速度指定とかもあるんだよね。
Speed, ah, there are speed limits too, right?
ちょっとわしが、いよっ、これぐらいかな？
Let me, oop, about this much?
ここに置いとこかな。
I'll put it here.
時速何キロ？
What's the speed in km/h?
なるほど。S字、S字付きの…え、ちょちょちょ。
I see. An S-curve... wait wait wait.
なんかボタン、ボタンあるのじゃ。ボタンがあるのじゃ。
There are buttons here. There are buttons!
これボタン押したらやばいやつ？
Are these buttons dangerous if pressed?
やばいやつ？
Dangerous ones?
えーっと、じゃあ時速2キロで、前進！
Um, then at 2 km/h, forward!
了解〜、ゆっくり2キロで前進するね。地雷は触れないよ？
Understood~, moving forward slowly at 2 km/h. Don't touch the landmines, okay?
地雷？地雷があるのじゃ？右にちょっと曲がるのじゃ！
Landmines? There are landmines? Turn a bit to the right!
ちょっと右に寄せるよ〜、地雷に触れないように慎重に！お兄…よしよしよしよし！
Moving a bit to the right~, carefully so we don't touch the mines! Bro... alright alright!
ちょ、地雷やばいのじゃ！もっと右なのだじゃ！
Woah, the landmines are dangerous! More to the right!
うん、もっと右だね。左前方に地雷があるのは知ってるから、ちゃんと…お兄さん？
Yeah, even more right. I know there's a landmine ahead to the left, so properly... bro?
時速2キロやばいか。の。時速2キロやばいか。でも地雷踏むよりましじゃろ？
Is 2 km/h bad? Is 2 km/h bad? But it's better than stepping on a landmine, right?
まっすぐなのだじゃ！…はいはいはいはい！地雷は左前方にあるから、真ん中キープで通るのが…お兄さん、これでいい？
Straight ahead! ...Yes yes yes yes! The landmine is to the front left, so keeping to the middle is... bro, is this good?
左に進むのだじゃ！
Move to the left!
うん、左に寄せるね。左前方に地雷があるから、ちょっと控えめに。曲がれるはず！安全運転なのだじゃ。安全通過できるはず！
Yeah, pulling to the left. There's a landmine ahead to the left, so keep it modest. We should be able to turn! Drive safely. We can pass safely!
もっと左！もっと左！やばい！地雷も踏む！
More left! More left! Oh no! We'll step on a landmine!
もっと左って言われると焦るけど、左前方と右前方に地雷があるんだよ、お兄さん。これでどう？
When you tell me more left, I panic, but there are landmines front-left and front-right, bro. How's this?
わかった！止まるね。ちょっと焦った声で言われるとこっちも焦る…。直すよ、お兄さん。後ろに下がるのだじゃ。
Understood! I'll stop. When you say it in a panicked voice, I panic too... I'll fix it, bro. Moving backwards.
ゆっくりバックするね。地雷に近づかないように、できるだけ中央から…安全？
Backing up slowly. To avoid getting close to the mines, keeping as central as possible... safe?
上手上手！上手上手！あんばいが上手！あんばいが…ちょっと遅いな。
Good job! Good job! Great handling! The handling is... a bit slow.
時速3キロで下がるのだじゃ。
Backing up at 3 km/h.
ゆっくり3キロで下がるね。あ、さて…。下がるだけでも左右に寄れないように気をつけるよ、お兄さん。止ま…止まるのだじゃ！
Backing up slowly at 3 km/h. Ah, now then... I'll be careful not to drift left or right even when backing up, bro. Stop... stop!
了解、少しだけ減速するね。ちょっと地雷が前後左右にあるから、集中して安…お兄さん。もうちょい早くするか。安全第一で行くよ、お兄さん。前、左に…時速5キロで進むのだじゃ！
Understood, slowing down just a bit. There are landmines all around, so concentrating safely... bro. Maybe a bit faster. Safety first, bro. Forward, left... moving at 5 km/h!
了解、前に進んでちょっと左に寄せるね。注意、地雷は前方と右前方よ、お兄さん。もっと右だね。了解…。地雷は前方と右前方にあるから、今度はちゃん…よ、お兄さん。止まるのだじゃ！止まるのだじゃ！
Understood, moving forward and pulling a bit left. Caution, the mines are ahead and front-right, bro. More right. Understood... the mines are ahead and front-right, so this time properly... bro. Stop! Stop!
お兄さん、笑ってるね。ちょここっちの集中が見乱れちゃうから、もうちょっと落ち着いて。今のままだと地雷の真ん中付近だったので、慎重に行くよ。
Bro, you're laughing. It messes up my concentration, so calm down a bit. Right now we were right in the middle of the mines, so I'll go carefully.
うん、分かった。今のままじゃちょっと危ないから、ゆっくり後ろに下がるね。動かしすぎないようにちゃんと見ててよ。…うん、遅い。止まるのだじゃ！
Yeah, understood. As is it's a bit dangerous, so I'll back up slowly. Watch carefully so I don't move too much. ...Yeah, too slow. Stop!
了解、止まるね。時速5キロで左に進むのだじゃ！落ち着いてからまた考えるよ、お兄さん。了解、ゆっくり5キロで左に寄せるね。地雷は前と右前にあるから、よ、お兄さん。これでどう？
Understood, stopping. Moving left at 5 km/h! I'll think again after calming down, bro. Understood, pulling left slowly at 5 km/h. The mines are front and front-right, so... bro. How's this?
了解、停止するね！焦るのは分かるけど、もう安全第一で行こう。地雷にずれないように気をつけて…
Understood, stopping! I know you're panicked, but let's go safety first. Be careful not to slip on the mines...
この芋とひっくり返しても同時なくて、すごいのだじゃ！え、びびってもだめ？なんじゃ？なんなのだじゃ！
This potato... even flipped over it didn't match, amazing! Huh, getting scared is no good either? What is this? What's going on!
難しくない？
Isn't it difficult?
誰ができる？
Who can do this?
時速4キロでまっすぐ進んでちょっと右なのだじゃ！
Moving straight at 4 km/h and a bit to the right!
うん、まっすぐ走ってからちょっと右に寄せるね。地雷は今のところ余…よお兄さん。あ、上手上手！上手上手！上手上手！うまいうまい！すごい上手上手上手！
Yeah, running straight then pulling a bit right. The mines for now... bro. Ah, good good! Good good! Good good! Great great! So amazing!
え、ほんとにそう言ってくれる？うれしいけど、ちょっと照れる〜。集中して続けるねお兄さん。ほらねって言われると、私ちょっと勝ち気になるな〜。ありがとう、お兄さんから、気をつけてね。
Eh, really saying that? I'm happy, but a bit embarrassed~. I'll keep concentrating, bro. When you say "see?", I get a bit competitive~. Thanks, bro, take care.
やっぱ褒めて育てる！
That's right, praise raises you!
左に進むのじゃ！
Go to the left!
了解〜、左に寄せるね。
Understood, I'll pull to the left.
いけるか？
Can you make it?
ちょっとやばいか。止まるのじゃ！
This is a bit close. Stop!
了解、止まるね。地雷は前方と
Understood, stopping. The mines are
右前方にあるから、落ち着いて整えて。
ahead and right, so calm down.
後ろに戻るのじゃ！
Go back!
うん、少しだけ後ろに下がるね。
Yeah, I'll back up a bit.
焦らず整えつつ戻るように。
Stay calm and back up.
上手上手
Great, great!
上手上手、上手上手
上手じゃけど、こっからどうしようわし？
Good, but what do I do from here?
どうしよう、どこまで下がろう？
What should I do, how far back?
えっとな、よし。
Let's see, alright.
止まるのじゃ！
Stop!
うん、止まるね。
Yeah, stopping.
了解、止まるのじゃね。
Understood, stop.
左…めっちゃ左に進むのじゃ！
Left... go way to the left!
うん、止まるのじゃね。
Yeah, stopping.
今から左にめっちゃ寄せるよ。
I'm pulling way left now.
ストップのじゃ！ストップのじゃ！
Stop! Stop!
うわぁーーー！
Whoa!
了解、止まるのじゃね！
Understood, stopping!
今の感じだと地雷はあるから…
The way it is, there are mines...
お兄さんびっくりしてる？
Are you surprised, big brother?
でも左に曲がる時にめちゃくちゃ左って言わなきゃいけない感じか。
But I have to say "extreme left" for every turn?
えっとな、まっすぐ時速4キロで前に行ってちょっと右なのだ！
Straight at 4 km/h, then a bit right!
了解〜、まっすぐ進んでから右に寄せるね。
Understood, go straight then pull right.
お兄さん、褒めてくれるのうれしいよ〜。
Big brother, I'm happy you praise me.
もう、そんなに褒められると照れる…。
Geez, being praised makes me shy...
でも気を抜かないように、ちゃんと見ててね。
But don't let your guard down, watch closely.
ストップのじゃ！
Stop!
了解〜、止まるのじゃね。
Understood, stopping.
地雷は前方と右前方向にあるから…90度？
Mines are ahead and right... 90 degrees?
めっちゃ左に90度曲がるのじゃ！
Turn 90 degrees sharply left!
わかったよ。左にぐっと切るって言うけど、90度は怖いな。
Understood. You say crank left, but 90 degrees is scary.
無理しないで安全に小さく曲がるよお兄さん。
I'll take a safe, small turn, big brother.
いけるかな？
Can we make it?
あれ、進まんな。
Huh, it's not moving.
進んで、めちゃくちゃ左、90度曲がるのじゃ！
Move forward, turn 90 degrees left!
うん、ちょっとだけ前進してから左にぐっと切るね。
Yeah, move forward a bit then crank left.
90度となると…当たらないようにするよお兄さん。
At 90 degrees... I'll avoid hitting anything.
このへんでまっすぐ進むのじゃ！
Go straight around here!
了解〜、ここはまっすぐ進むね。
Understood, going straight here.
了解、止まるのじゃね。
Understood, stopping.
地雷は前方と右前方にあるから、今の位置なら安全だよ。
Mines are ahead and right, safe here.
ちょっとだけ左に寄せるね。前方と右前方に余裕あるから。
Pulling slightly left. There's room ahead and right.
ストップのじゃ！
Stop!
了解、止まるのじゃね。
Understood, stopping.
後ろに少し下がって、安全に切り替えるよ。
Back up a bit to switch safely.
うん、後ろにちょっと下がるね。前方と右前方に地雷があるから。
Yeah, backing up a bit. Mines ahead and right.
止まるのじゃ！そしてちょっと左に進むのじゃ！
Stop! Then go a bit to the left!
了解、止まるのじゃね。前方コンディション整えつつ、ちょっと左に。
Understood, stopping. Adjusting position, a bit left.
うん、上手！進んでなくない？
Yeah, great! Aren't we moving?
進んでなくない？めに、左にちょっと進むのじゃ！
Aren't we moving? Go forward and a bit left!
うん、前に進んでからちょっとだけ左に寄せるね。
Yeah, move forward then pull a bit left.
地雷は前方と右前方にあるから、そこを避けるように。もっと左だよ！
Mines ahead and right, avoid them. More left!
上手上手なのだ！
Great job!
うれしい…今のちょっと照れるな。
I'm happy... that makes me shy.
右に、ちょっと右に進むのじゃ！
To the right, go a bit to the right!
うん、ちょっと右に寄せるね。地雷は右後方に…
Yeah, pulling right. Mines are rear-right...
もちょい右に進むのじゃ！
Go a bit more right!
えらいえらい！すごいすごいすごい！
Good job! Amazing, amazing!
もうちょっと右だね、
A bit more to the right,
了解。
Got it.
地雷は前方と右側にあるから、危ないよ、お兄さん。
There are mines ahead and to the right, so watch out, mister.
ああ、これがプロ。
Ah, now that's a pro.
いいのじゃいいのじゃ。
That's fine, that's fine.
よしよしよし。
Good, good, good.
超遅いけど、事故りよりましなのじゃ！
It's super slow, but better than crashing!
よいよしよしよしよし、ゴールなんじゃない？
Good, good, good, isn't that the goal?
のじゃ！
No!
うわ、教えるのおそすぎない？遅すぎるのじゃ。
Whoa, isn't your guidance way too late? Too late.
うん。
Yeah.
よいしょ。
Heave-ho.
駐車？このくらいなら楽勝だよ。
Parking? This is a piece of cake.
うわ、これめっちゃ危なくない？
Whoa, isn't this super dangerous?
よそんのさ、ひとさまの車にぶつけちゃったらさ、弁償じゃろ？余裕で弁償じゃろ？
If we bump into someone else's car, we'd have to pay damages, right? Easily pay damages, right?
えっと、うーん、時速４キロで右に曲がって進むのじゃ。
Um, let's see, move forward turning right at 4 km/h.
了解、ちょっとだけ右に曲がって進むね。前方注意して、曲がり切る…
Got it, moving forward turning right a bit. Watch ahead, finish the turn...
上手上手上手、キープするよ。
Good, good, good, keeping it.
ちょっと左に進むのじゃ。
Move a bit to the left.
了解お兄さん。ちょっとだけ左に向けて進むね。急がず、ちゃんと狭い場所に当たらないようにするよ。
Got it, mister. Moving forward angled slightly left. Don't rush, make sure not to hit tight spots.
まっすぐなのだ！
Straight ahead!
うん、まっすぐね。安心して進むよ、お兄さん。狭い場所だし、今はそのままでいいから。
Yeah, straight. I'll drive with peace of mind, mister. It's a tight spot, so just stay as you are.
左なのだ！曲がるのだ！
To the left! Turn!
了解、左曲がるね。ゆっくり、前方確認しながらハンドル切るよ、お兄さん。
Got it, turning left. Slow down, turn the wheel while checking ahead, mister.
了解、止まるのだね。上にものがあるのか。
Got it, stopping. Is there something above?
息を止める気持ちで慎重にね。お兄さん。
Be careful enough to hold your breath, mister.
後ろに曲がりながらハンドルを左に回すのじゃ。
Turn the wheel to the left while backing up.
了解お兄さん。後ろに少し下げながら左にハンドル切るね。
Got it, mister. I'll back up a bit and turn the wheel left.
人間はやっぱりミラーを信じる生き物だから、ちゃんと確認してしてから動くよ。
Humans are creatures that trust mirrors after all, so I'll check properly before moving.
ストップなのだ！
Stop!
了解、止まるのじゃね。前方に物があるから、
Got it, stopping. There's something ahead, so
前方に90度右に…待って、前方に90度左に進むのじゃ！
Ahead 90 degrees to the right... wait, move 90 degrees to the left ahead!
うん、前方だけ確認して、次に90度左に曲がるから準備するね。ちょっとだよ、お兄さん。
Yeah, just check ahead and get ready to turn 90 degrees left next. Just a bit, mister.
ギリギリギリギリ！
Barely making it!
前方に物がある感じだから、息を止めるくらい慎重にね、お兄さん。
It feels like there's something ahead, so be as careful as holding your breath, mister.
ハンドルを右に回しながら後ろに進むのじゃ！
Back up while turning the wheel to the right!
了解お兄さん。ハンドルを右に切りながら後ろに進むね。ぎこちないけど、全くに行くよ。
Got it, mister. Backing up while turning the wheel right. It's awkward, but I'll go safely.
うんうんうんうん、上手上手上手。このへんで…
Yeah yeah yeah, good good good. Around here...
ストップなのだ！
Stop!
前方に進んで、ちょっと左に進むのじゃ。ここでしっかり止めて確認するね。
Move forward, and move a little to the left. Stop firmly here and check.
うん、ちょっとだけ左に進むね。前方は安全だから、焦らず微調整して…
Yeah, moving just a little left. Ahead is safe, so make fine adjustments without rushing...
もう少し左だね…。前方に物があるから、キリッと避ける感じで、お兄さん。
A bit more to the left... There's something ahead, so avoid it sharply, mister.
もうちょっと左だね…。焦らずゆっくり寄せるよ、お兄さん。今のところ、ちゃんと真ん中に持っていくね。
A bit more to the left... Slowly and calmly pull closer, mister. So far, keeping it right in the middle.
了解お兄さん、止まるのじゃ。後ろに下がってハンドルを右に回すのじゃ。
Got it, mister, time to stop. Back up and turn the wheel to the right.
了解お兄さん。後ろに下がってハンドルを右に切って曲がるね。ちょっとだけ余裕を持って動かすから、変な音はしないと思うよ。
Got it, mister. Backing up and turning the wheel right to curve. I'll move with margin, so no weird noises.
了解お兄さん。止まるのじゃ。めっちゃ左にハンドルを回して進むのじゃ。ここでちゃんと停止して状況を見てから次にいくよ。
Got it, mister. Stop. Turn the wheel way to the left and move. Stop properly here and check before moving on.
了解お兄さん。めっちゃ左に振って進むね。前方をちょっとだけ見るけど、持ち替え前提でいくよ。
Got it, mister. Swinging way left to go. I'll look ahead a bit, but proceeding assuming I'll readjust.
了解お兄さん。止まるのじゃ。前方に物がある感じだから、ここでしっかり止めてからまた考えるね。
Got it, mister. Stop. It feels like there's an obstacle ahead, so I'll stop securely here and think again.
難しい、難しいけど、弟ちゃん、わりと最初に思ってたより物分かりが良い。
It's hard, hard, but little bro is understanding things a lot better than I first thought.
意外と物分かりが良い。
Surprisingly good at understanding.
なんかブチ切れるゲームって聞いてたんだけど、切れなくてよさそうなのじゃ。次！
I heard it's a rage-inducing game, but looks like he won't lose his temper. Next!
やっぱね、あの、怒るとね、人は委縮しちゃうからね、良くないのじゃ。駐車場を出てください。
See, when you get angry, people get intimidated, so it's not good. Please leave the parking lot.
駐車場出るよ。何この音？何この音？何の音？
Leaving the parking lot. What's this sound? What's this sound? What sound?
前に進んで、いっぱい右に曲がるのじゃ！
Move forward and turn all the way to the right!
了解お兄さん、前に進んでいっぱい右に曲がるね。タイミングはちゃんとしてくれると助かるよ。
Got it, mister. Moving forward and turning all the way right. It helps if you time it right.
何この音？ボンボン言ってる。いっぱいね。何この
What's this sound? It's going thud-thud. Plenty, huh. What's thi-
おっ、上手上手。
Oh, good, good.
何かこのボンボンって音？
What's this bon-bon sound?
何かこのボンボンって音、何の音なのじゃ？
What's this bon-bon sound, what sound is it?
分かんない、ストップのじゃ。
I don't know. Stop.
このボンって音何？
What's this bon sound?
ねえねえ、このボンって音何？変な動きはしないから安心して。
Hey hey, what's this bon sound? It won't do anything weird, so don't worry.
お兄さん、この車のエンジン音かな？それか周りの警告音の可能性もあるかも。ちょっと確認してみるね。
Big brother, is this the car's engine sound? Or maybe a warning sound. Let me check.
よし、じゃあ、前に、時速4キロで進むのじゃ。
Alright then, forward, moving at 4 km/h.
うん、ちょっと右に寄るのじゃ。車が出るところだから、周りに注…
Yeah, leaning a bit to the right. Since cars are coming out, watch the sur...
うん、上手上手。前方も後方も大丈夫そうだから、スッと調整していくよ、お兄さん。
Yeah, good, good. Front and back look fine, so I'll smoothly adjust, big brother.
左に、進むのじゃ。
Moving to the left.
了解お兄さん、右に寄るのじゃ。道も空いてるから、スムーズに進むね。前方も後方も安全そうだし、了解お兄さん、右に寄るのじゃ。
Got it big brother, leaning to the right. The road is clear, so it'll go smoothly. Front and back look safe, got it big brother, leaning to the right.
えっと、左なのじゃ！
Um, to the left!
了解お兄さん、左に寄るのじゃ。前方に物が近いから、ゆっくり止まって確認するよ。ハンドルを右に回しながら、後ろに進むのじゃ！
Got it big brother, leaning to the left. Something is close ahead, so I'll stop slowly and check. Turning the steering wheel right while moving backwards!
で、このボンボンって音何？了解お兄さん、ハンドルを右に切って、後ろに進むのね。ちょっとだけびっくりするけど、やってみるよ。
And what's this bon-bon sound? Got it big brother, turning the steering wheel right and going backwards. It's a bit surprising, but I'll try.
止まるのじゃ！
Stop!
ねえ、このバンバンって音何か気になるのあるのじゃ？まっすぐ進んで、左に曲がるのじゃ！
Hey, is there something bothering you about this bang-bang sound? Go straight and turn left!
了解お兄さん、前に少し進んでから左に曲がるね。緊張してるけど…ストップなのじゃ、ストップ！了解お兄さん、めっちゃ左…
Got it big brother, go forward a bit and turn left. I'm nervous... Stop, stop! Got it big brother, super left...
ちょっと擦った。了解お兄さん、ちょっと擦った。大丈夫か？耐えか？前方にもうがあるっぽいから、ここでしっかり止まってから考える…後ろに進むのじゃ！
Scraped a bit. Got it big brother, scraped a bit. Is it okay? Can it take it? There seems to be something ahead, so stop firmly here and think... Moving backwards!
ハンドルを右に切…右に回して後ろなのじゃ。了解お兄さん、後ろに進むのじゃ。これは耐えか？ハンドルはまっすぐにして、ゆっくり下がるよ。
Turn the steering wheel right... turn right and go backwards. Got it big brother, moving backwards. Can it take this? Straighten the wheel and go down slowly.
はい、耐えぐらいか？うんうんうんうん。
Yeah, about enough to take it? Yeah yeah yeah yeah.
煙出て出たらだめかな？ストップのじゃ！
Is it bad if smoke comes out? Stop!
了解お兄さん、ストップなのじゃ。えっと、左にめっちゃ曲がるのじゃ！今は静かに止まって確認するね。左めちゃ切るのじゃ。
Got it big brother, stop. Um, turning super left! Now I'll stop quietly and check. Turning hard left.
あ、いい上手上手。ジャムも言ってる。上手上手、上手ーーっ！
Ah, good, good good. Jam is also saying it. Good good, good—!
いよいよ道路に出るの？すごく楽しみ。「ここからは私が」上手なのだじゃ！燃えてる車で行動に出たら怒られる？
Finally going out on the road? So excited. 'From here on I'll...' So good! Will I get scolded if I act with a burning car?
私が運転？大丈夫？
I'm driving? Is it okay?
え、きゅ、気をつけてね。
Uh, car-, be careful.
気をつけるのじゃ！気をつけるのじゃ！
Be careful! Be careful!
了解お兄さん、気をつけるのじゃね。前方は空いてるけど、ちょっと緊張してるから走りながら注意するよ。
Got it big brother, be careful. The front is open, but I'm a bit nervous so I'll be careful while driving.
今行くのじゃ、左！前！了解お兄さん、左前方に進むね。
Going now, left! Front! Got it big brother, moving to the left front.
ちょっとだけ釣り方にいきたいから、周りを見てから、慎重に行くよ。おお、デンジャー！デンジャー！ストップのじゃ！後ろに進むのじゃ！
I want to lean a bit diagonally, so after looking around, I'll go carefully. Oh, danger! Danger! Stop! Move backwards!
了解お兄さん、ストップしてから、後ろに下がるね。ハンドルはまっすぐで、ゆっくり動かすよ。詰まってる、詰まってる。
Got it big brother, after stopping, I'll go backwards. The wheel is straight, moving slowly. It's jammed, jammed.
あ、進みだした。え、これ入るの難しくない？
Ah, it started moving. Eh, isn't it hard to enter this?
前進むのじゃ！左！時速20キロ！
Move forward! Left! 20 km/h!
止まるのじゃ、止まるのじゃ！Uターンしてください。
Stop, stop! Please make a U-turn.
え、なんか、な、光った？え、お、おいおいおいおい！
Eh, like, wh-, it glowed? Eh, h-, hey hey hey hey!
了解お兄さん、止まるのじゃ。Uターン中だから、ここでしっかり停止して…速くない？
Got it big brother, stop. Since it's during a U-turn, stop firmly here... Isn't it fast?
え、なに？なになに？速くない？
Eh, what? What what? Isn't it fast?
え？車光ってる！う、う、う、う！
Eh? The car is glowing! W-, w-, w-, w!
車めっちゃ光ってるのじゃ！何この街？この街やばいのじゃ、この街やばい！
The car is super glowing! What is this city? This city is dangerous, this city is dangerous!
ちょっ、ちょっ、ちょっ、そりゃUターンするよね！危ないもんね！Uターンどうやってするの、この街で？
Wait, wait, wait, of course I'll make a U-turn! It's dangerous! How do you make a U-turn in this city?
どう、どうしろと、この街で？どうしようかな？
Wh-, what am I supposed to do in this city? What should I do?
Uターンするのじゃ！前行って左！
Make a U-turn! Go forward and left!
了解お兄さん、Uターンするのじゃ。前に出てきながら左に切っていく…いけるかな？後方の安全を確認しつつ…ちょっ、ちょっ、いや、いけるかな？
Got it big brother, making a U-turn. Coming forward while turning left... Can I make it? While checking safety behind... Wha-, wha-, no, can I make it?
気をつけてね！気をつけてね！めっ、めっちゃ左！
Be careful! Be careful! Sup-, super left!
もうちょい左だね…まだ曲が途中だから、ゆっくり位置を合わ…あっ、ちょっ、ちょっ、がんばれっ、ああっ！
A bit more left... Still in the middle of turning, slowly aligning position... Ah, wait, wait, do your best, aaah!
ドライブフェイルド！もう一度！
Drive failed! One more time!
もうじゃあ！えっ、この、こ…
No way! Eh, this, th...
この街どうすればいいの？どうしたら？どうしたら生きていけるのじゃ？
What should I do in this city? What should I do? How can I survive?
え、ちょっ、ま、まずい！まずい、一筋縄ではいかない。
Eh, wait, th-, bad! Bad, it's not going to be easy.
え、じゃあもう最初から左に行った方がいい？
Eh, then should I have gone left from the very beginning?
いー
Eek...
どうすんのがいいんだろ。頑張れよ妹。
What should I do? Do your best, little sister!
時速4キロで右に進むのじゃ。
At 4 km/h, proceed to the right.
了解お兄さん、右に進むのじゃ。左に行きたい気持ちはあるけど、ここはちゃんと従って運転するよ。
Roger, big brother, moving right. I want to go left, but I'll follow the rules and drive properly.
うーん、どうしようかな。どうしようかな、もう早速左に出ちゃうのがいいのかの。左に出ちゃう、かな。むず。
Hmm, what should I do? Should I just head out to the left right away? Head left, maybe? So hard.
まっすぐ、まっすぐ進むのじゃ！
Go straight, keep going straight!
あ、やったね。前はちょっと斜だけど、まっすぐ方向に整えたい、お兄さん。ちょっと左に寄せて、前進しながら整えるね。余裕があるから慎重に動くよ。
Ah, we did it. It's a bit diagonal, but I want to straighten it out, big brother. Shift slightly left and straighten while moving forward. We have room, so move carefully.
上手上手。上手だげと、道路に侵入ね。
Good job, good job. Well done, now enter the road.
ちょっと右なのじゃ。はいはい、上手上手。左なのじゃ！
A bit to the right. Yes, yes, good job. To the left!
了解お兄さん、右に寄るね。前方は空いてるから、上手上手お兄さん。はい上手、はい上手。
Roger, big brother, shifting right. The way ahead is clear, good job big brother. Yes, good job.
いよいよ道路に出るの？すごく楽しみ。「ここからは私が運転してみるね。
Are we finally hitting the road? I'm so excited. "From here on, I'll try driving."
左、左行くのじゃ、左！
Left, go left, left!
了解お兄さん、左にぐっと寄るね。前方は空いてるから、今のままチャ
Roger, big brother, cutting hard to the left. The front is clear, so stay as we are...
了解そうお兄さん、もう一回左に切るね。前方は空いてるから安心して、
Roger, big brother, turning left once more. The front is clear, so don't worry,
止まるのじゃ、止まるのじゃ、止まるのじゃ！
Stop, stop, stop!
大変！Uターンできないんだけど。
Oh no, I can't U-turn!
了解お兄さん、止まるのじゃ。Uターン中だから、ここでしっかり停止して周りを見てから次の
Roger, big brother, stop. Since we're mid-U-turn, come to a complete stop here, check around, and then...
左にUターンなのじゃ！
U-turn to the left!
了解お兄さん、周り見てから左にUターンするのじゃ。今は静かにして気をつけてね。
Roger, big brother, look around and U-turn left. Keep quiet for now and be careful.
この、この距離で曲がれるかの？
Can we make the turn in this distance?
めっちゃ気をつけて、左にUターンなのじゃ！
Be extremely careful and U-turn to the left!
了解お兄さん、めっちゃ気をつけて左のUターンするのじゃ。焦らず慎重に、車幅を合わせるよ。
Roger, big brother, being super careful making a left U-turn. Don't panic, adjust the vehicle width carefully.
止まるのじゃ！
Stop!
了解お兄さん、止まるのじゃ。ちょっと後ろの様子を見て、後ろの黒長がいなくなったらちょっとバックするのじゃ。
Roger, big brother, stop. Check the rear situation, and once the black car is gone, back up a bit.
ちょっ後ろの車が全部お亡くなりになるからこれから、この犠牲を尊い犠牲を眺めた後に、うん、尊い犠牲を眺めた後に、ちょっと後ろ下がるのじゃ。そして止まるのじゃ。
Since all the cars behind us are going to perish from now on, after gazing upon this noble sacrifice... yeah, after gazing upon that noble sacrifice, back up a bit. And then stop.
了解お兄さん、ちょっとだけ後ろに下がって、止まるのじゃ。位置を少し調整して、ここで落ち着くね。
Roger, big brother, back up just a little and stop. Adjust position slightly and calm down here.
ちょっと後ろ下がるのじゃ！
Back up a bit more!
了解お兄さん、軽く後ろに下がってから、止まるのじゃね。今回はちょっとだけ車が動くのが怖いな。
Roger, big brother, backing up slightly and then stopping. This time, I'm a bit scared of the car moving.
後ろに下がるのじゃ！
Back up!
了解お兄さん、後ろに下がるのじゃ。まっすぐにして、ゆっくり動かすね。
Roger, big brother, backing up. Straighten it out and move slowly.
了解お兄さん、止まってから少し下がるね。ごめんね、ちょっと緊張し動くよ。
Roger, big brother, stopping then backing up a bit. Sorry, I'm a bit nervous, moving now.
左に、めっちゃ左に、Uターンなのじゃ！
To the left, super left, U-turn!
きゅるっと左に切ってUターンするのじゃ。ちょっとハンドルが重い気行くね、お兄さん。
Spin the wheel hard left and U-turn. The steering feels a bit heavy, doesn't it, big brother.
いけるのじゃ。上手上手上手上手なのじゃ！
We can do it. Good job, good job, well done!
お兄さん、良いところまで来たね～。ただ、もう少し落ち着いて確認して、進むよ。
Big brother, we've come a good way. But let's calm down, check things, and proceed.
めっちゃ左に曲がるのじゃ！
Turn super hard to the left!
了解お兄さん、めっちゃ左に曲がるのじゃ。前方は空いてるから、ちょっと、ぶつかんないようにね。消火栓とかね危ないからね。前方は空いてるから、上手上手上手なのじゃ！
Roger, big brother, turning super hard left. The front is clear, so watch out not to crash. Fire hydrants and stuff are dangerous. Front is clear, good job!
お兄さん、止まるのじゃ。前と後ろは空いてるけど、今はゆっくり
Big brother, stop. Front and back are clear, but now slowly...
ちょっと左に曲がるのじゃ。
Turn slightly to the left.
了解お兄さん、ちょっとだけ左に曲がるね。急な感じはしないから、もう少しやってみるよ。
Roger, big brother, turning slightly left. It doesn't feel sudden, so I'll try a bit more.
お兄さん、まっすぐ進むのじゃ。少し余裕があるから、ちゃんと
Big brother, go straight. We have some leeway, so properly...
うわぁっ！何あれ！？
Whoa! What is that?!
何あれ？なんか来た！
What's that? Something's coming!
めっ、速度上げるのじゃ！50キロ！
S-Speed up! 50 km/h!
お兄さん、その速度は危ないよ～。ここは落ち着いて、まずは安全第一。
Big brother, that speed is dangerous. Calm down, safety first.
左車線行くのじゃ！
Go to the left lane!
了解お兄さん、左に切りたいところだけど、今は安全第一。まずは止まれね。
Roger, big brother, I want to switch left, but safety first. First, stop.
右車線！
Right lane!
了解お兄さん、ここで止まるのじゃ。巨体のあれ、怖いよね。まずは落とそう。
Roger, big brother, stop here. That huge thing is scary. Let's drop speed first.
進むのじゃ、進むのじゃ！
Keep going, keep going!
お兄さん、クラクションの音だね。怖いよ。
Big brother, that's the sound of a horn. It's scary.
ちょっ、ちょっ、やばい！進むのじゃ、進むのじゃ！逃げる！右車線、右車線！
Wait, wait, oh no! Keep going, keep going! Escape! Right lane, right lane!
右車線！のじゃー！
Right lane! Nooo!
なるほど、なるほど。あの、なんじゃこのゲーム
I see, I see. Um, what kind of game is this?
なんだこのゲーム、そういうのもある？
What is this game? Is that a thing too?
てか、あのさ、思ったんじゃが、他の車が逃げてくれなかったらさ、他の車が逃げてくれなかったらわしたち逃げられなくない？
I mean, you know, I was thinking, if the other cars didn't run away... if the other cars didn't run away, wouldn't we not be able to escape?
じゃから、ええと、どうじゃろな？
So, um, I wonder what we should do?
どうじゃろな？空いてるところを指示して、他の犠牲を見つめながら逃げる感じかの？
What do you think? Like directing to open spaces and escaping while watching other sacrifices?
難しいのじゃ！運転ってこんな難しいのじゃ！歩道が空いてる？歩道ってさすがに炎上しない？
It's so hard! Driving is this hard! Sidewalks are open? Wouldn't a sidewalk cause an uproar?
さすがに歩道は怒られないか？
Wouldn't sidewalks at least get us in trouble?
よし、時速4キロで右に進むのじゃ！
Alright, let's move right at 4 km/h!
時速4キロで右に進むのじゃ！
Move right at 4 km/h!
了解お兄さん、時速4キロで右に進むね。前方は空いてるから、ちょっと右に寄っていくよ。
Understood, brother, moving right at 4 km/h. The front is clear, so I'll nudge a bit to the right.
了解お兄さん、めっちゃ右に切るのじゃ。ちょっと怖いけど、ちゃんと見ながら慎重に行くね。
Understood, brother, turning sharply right. It's a bit scary, but I'll watch carefully and go cautiously.
了解お兄さん、真っ直ぐ戻すね。前も後も空いてるから、ちゃんと合わせて進むよ。
Understood, brother, straightening back out. Both front and back are clear, so I'll match and move forward.
いやあ、どうしようかの？どうする妹？この町から逃げない？わしたちこの町ちょっとやばいのじゃ。
Man, what should we do? What do you say, little sister? Should we not escape from this town? This town is a bit dangerous for us.
わかったお兄さん。左に曲がるのじゃ。前方は空いてるから、ちょっと気をつけて曲がるね。
Understood, brother. We'll turn left. The front is open, so I'll turn with care.
了解お兄さん、右に曲がるのじゃ。後方は空いてるから、ちょっとだけ右へ寄る感じで進んでいこ。
Understood, brother, we're turning right. The back is clear, so let's proceed while nudging a bit to the right.
了解お兄さん、後ろに... ぶつかっちゃった！後ろは空いてるから、ハンドルは真っ直ぐにして安全を優先するよ。
Understood, brother, backward... We crashed! The back is clear, so keep the steering wheel straight and prioritize safety.
後ろに進んで、ハンドルを右に回すのじゃ！
Move backward and turn the steering wheel to the right!
了解お兄さん、まずは真っ直ぐ下がって、ハンドルを右に切る感じでいくね。安全重視で動くよ。
Understood, brother, first back up straight, and go with the feel of turning the wheel right. Moving with safety first.
後ろにそのまま真っ直ぐ進むのじゃ！
Continue moving straight back!
了解お兄さん、安全重視で、後ろにそのまま真っ直ぐ下がるのじゃ。焦らずゆっくり、かなり慎重に行くよ。
Understood, brother, safety first, back straight up as is. Without rushing, slowly and quite cautiously.
右に、前に、真っ直ぐ進むのじゃ！
Right, forward, move straight ahead!
了解お兄さん、右に前に進むのじゃ。真っ直ぐ進むけど、ちょっとだけ右に寄せるから安心して。
Understood, brother, moving right and forward. I'll go straight, but I'll nudge a bit right, so rest assured.
時速5キロで後ろに進むのじゃ！
Move backward at 5 km/h!
了解お兄さん、時速5キロで後ろに進むのじゃ。慎重に、あんまり大きく曲がらないように気をつけるね。
Understood, brother, backing up at 5 km/h. Carefully, being careful not to turn too sharply.
了解お兄さん、止まるのじゃ。いまは安全を優先して...
Understood, brother, stop. Right now, prioritize safety...
めっちゃ右に進むのじゃ！
Move sharply to the right!
了解お兄さん、めっちゃ右に進むのじゃ。前は空いてるから、少し...
Understood, brother, moving sharply right. The front is open, so a little...
はい、ナイス！上手にできた！いよいよ道路に出るの？すごく楽しみ！わしが引き受けてあげるのじゃ。
Yes, nice! Well done! Are we finally hitting the road? I'm so excited! I'll take charge for you.
一番左の車線に入るのじゃ！
Enter the leftmost lane!
了解お兄さん、一番左の車線に入るのじゃ。前方は空いてるけど、ちょっとコスるだけなのに！
Understood, brother, enter the leftmost lane. The front is clear, but we just grazed it!
ちょっと、あの、満身って良くなくて、満身って良くないのじゃ。
Wait, um, overconfidence is no good, overconfidence is no good.
最初から慎重に行くよ。
I'll go cautiously from the start.
時速4キロで右に進むのじゃ！
Move right at 4 km/h!
了解お兄さん、時速4キロで右に進むのじゃ。前方は空いてるから、ぶつかりすぎると壊れちゃう判定っぽいので慎重に進めるね。
Understood, brother, moving right at 4 km/h. The front is clear, but since crashing too much seems to count as breaking, I'll proceed cautiously.
もっと右なのじゃ！ジャンキー的なのがあるのじゃ。
More to the right! There's something junk-like.
おっと、もっと右ね。前方は空いてるし、ちょっとだけ寄せて進めるよ。
Whoops, more to the right. The front is open, so I can nudge a bit and proceed.
このまま真っ直ぐなのじゃ！
Straight ahead like this!
了解お兄さん、そのまま真っ直ぐ進むのじゃ。前方は空いてるから、ちょっとだけ真っ直ぐに整えて...
Understood, brother, go straight ahead. The front is open, so straighten up just a little bit...
ギリギリいけるか！ギリギリいけるのじゃ！
Can we make it by a hair! We can make it by a hair!
ちょっと左なのじゃ！ちょっと左、ちょっと左。
A bit to the left! A bit left, a bit left.
了解お兄さん、ストップのじゃ。ストップのじゃじゃ、ストップのじゃないな、様子見よね。ストップのじゃないな。
Understood, brother, stop. Stop, no, not stop, checking it out. Not stop.
左に進むのじゃ！
Move to the left!
了解お兄さん、左に寄って前に少し進むのじゃ。前方は空いているから、余裕を持って調整していくよ。
Understood, brother, hug left and move forward a little. The front is open, so I'll adjust with plenty of room.
もっと左なのじゃ！
More to the left!
了解お兄さん、もう少し左に寄せるね。
Got it, big bro. I'll move a bit left.
前方と後方は空いているから、ちょっ…
The front and back are clear, so...
了解お兄さん、もうちょっと右に寄せるね。前方は空いているし、位置を整えながら進むよ。
Got it, big bro. I'll move a bit right. The front is clear, so I'll advance while adjusting position.
了解お兄さん、前に進んで左に寄せるのじゃ。
Got it, big bro. Move forward and pull over left.
前方は空いているから、ちょっとだけ斜めに置いておくっす。
The front's open, so I'll leave it at a slight angle.
いよいよ道路に出るの！すごく楽しみ！ここからは私が運転するよ。
I'm finally hitting the road! So excited! I'll be driving from here on.
気をつけるよ。一番左車線なのじゃ。
I'll be careful. It's the leftmost lane.
了解お兄さん、一番左の車線に入るのじゃ。ちょっとだけハンドルを切るけど、前方は空いているから安心して。
Got it, big bro. Entering the leftmost lane. I'll turn the wheel just a bit, but the front is clear, so don't worry.
他の車にぶつからないように左車線なのじゃ。
Stay in the left lane so we don't hit other cars.
了解お兄さん、左車線に寄せすぎないよう気をつけるね。
Got it, big bro. I'll be careful not to crowd the left lane too much.
前方は空いているけど、他の車にも気を付けるのじゃ。
The front is clear, but watch out for other cars too.
ストップなのじゃ！
Stop!
大変！Uターンできないんだけど。お兄ちゃん、これからどうすればいい？
Oh no! I can't U-turn. Big bro, what should I do now?
了解お兄さん、止まるのじゃ。高速は怖いし、ここでしっかり停止して様子を見るね。
Got it, big bro. We're stopping. Highways are scary, so let's stop here and see what's up.
Uターンするのじゃ！めっちゃ左に曲がるのじゃ！
Time to U-turn! Turn hard to the left!
了解お兄さん、めっちゃ左に切ってUターンするってことね。ちょっと慎重に行くよ。
Got it, big bro. You mean U-turning by cutting hard left. I'll go carefully.
高速なのに道が分かれてないのじゃ。
The road isn't divided even though it's a highway.
お兄さん、ちょっと褒められると照れる～。でもまだちゃんと言って…めっちゃ左にUターンなのじゃ！
Big bro, I get shy when praised. But wait, I'm still talking... U-turn super hard left!
了解お兄さん、めっちゃ左に切ってUターンするのじゃ。前方は空いているから慎重に位置を合わせるよ、お兄さん。
Got it, big bro. I'll cut hard left and U-turn. The front's open, so I'll align our position carefully, big bro.
了解お兄さん、真っすぐそのまま進むのじゃ。ちょっとだけ気持ちだけ…うわぁっ！何あれ！？
Got it, big bro. Go straight ahead. Just a little bit of- Whoa! What is that?!
トラックから逃げてくだ…早く時速30キロのじゃ！
Run away from the truck... Quickly, at 30 km/h!
了解お兄さん、今すぐ止まるのじゃ。巨大トラックが近いなら、焦ら…
Got it, big bro. Stop right now. If the giant truck is close, don't pan-
お兄さん、怖いのわかるけど、安全第一で止まるのじゃ。無理に出るっ…うわっ！やばい！
Big bro, I know you're scared, but safety first, stop. Don't force your way out- Whoa! Oh no!
多分、あのトラックが出てからの喋りは、単的に、単的に分かりやすく説明しないと、なんか多分割るのじゃと間違えちゃったっぽくて、止まるのじゃと間違えて止まっちゃったっぽいから、
Probably, after that truck appeared, my explanation needed to be brief and easy to understand... It seems I mistook it for 'stop' and accidentally stopped.
なんじゃろな。20キロ、30キロ早いて言われたから、でも30キロつったら早いて言われたから、出せる一番早い速さで前に進めとかかな？
What could it be? They said 20 or 30 km/h is fast, but since they said 30 km/h is fast, maybe it means move forward at the fastest possible speed?
29キロ、いったん一番早い速度で…うーん、かな？って言ってみよう。言ってみるのじゃ。
29 km/h, once at the fastest speed... hmm, is that it? Let's try saying that. Let's try saying it.
えーっと、時速4キロで右に進むのじゃ！
Um, move right at 4 km/h!
了解お兄さん、時速4キロで右に進むのじゃ。ちょっとだけ右に寄せてね。前も後も安全か確認するね。
Got it, big bro. Move right at 4 km/h. Shift a little to the right. Check if front and back are safe.
了解お兄さん、下がるのじゃ。まっすぐにして、ゆっくり動かすね。ちょっと緊張するけど、焦らずやるよ。
Got it, big bro. Back up. Straighten it out and move slowly. I'm a bit nervous, but I'll do it calmly.
時速29キロでめっちゃ右に曲がるのじゃ！お兄さん、ちょっと待って。時速29キロやめるね。ここは安全第一、
Turn super hard right at 29 km/h! Big bro, wait a second. Stop 29 km/h. Safety first here,
時速20キロで右に進むのじゃ！
Move right at 20 km/h!
わかったお兄さん。時速20キロで右に進むのじゃ。前方後方安全確認しながら進めるね。
Understood, big bro. Move right at 20 km/h. Advancing while checking front and rear safety.
了解お兄さん、左に振って走るね。前方が空いているから、ゆっくり曲がっていくよ。
Got it, big bro. I'll swing left and drive. The front is open, so I'll turn slowly.
了解お兄さん、後ろに下がるのじゃ。ハンドルはそのままで、ゆっくり動かすけど、緊張するけど、気をつけるね。
Got it, big bro. Back up. Keep the steering wheel as is and move slowly, I'm nervous, but I'll be careful.
了解お兄さん。まっすぐにして、ゆっくり後ろに下がるのじゃ。
Got it, big bro. Straighten it and back up slowly.
本当に下がってる？
Are you really backing up?
ちょっと確認するね。
Let me check.
本当に下がってる？
Are you really backing up?
下がってないじゃん。
You're not backing up at all!
妹ちゃん、後ろに下がるよ！
Little sis, I'm backing up!
やっと下がった。
Finally backed up.
了解お兄さん、後ろに下がるよ。ハンドルはまっすぐにして、ゆっくり動かすから安心して。
Got it, big bro, backing up. Keep the wheel straight and move slowly, so don't worry.
妹が弁解するから大丈夫なのかなじゃ。
My sister's making excuses, so is she really okay?
めっちゃ左に前に進むのじゃ！
Moving forward way to the left!
了解お兄さん、めっちゃ左に進むのじゃ。ちょっとハンドル切れるけど、ちゃんと見ながら安全にやるよ。
Got it, big bro, moving way to the left. I can turn the wheel a bit, but I'll watch carefully and do it safely.
なんか……頑張って説明しても、反映までが遅いのじゃ。
Man... even if I try hard to explain, the response time is so slow.
時速4キロで左に進むのじゃ！
Moving left at 4 km/h!
了解お兄さん、左に寄りつつ時速4キロで進むね。ちょっと緊張するけど、前も後も確認しながらね。
Got it, big bro, moving left at 4 km/h. I'm a bit nervous, but I'll check both front and back.
やっぱ優しく教えたい気持ちはありつつも、ありつつもでは、ありますのじゃ。
After all, while I want to teach gently... well, there is that part.
よし、行動出るよ。
Alright, taking action.
いよいよ道路に出るのじゃ！
We're finally hitting the road!
いよいよ道路に出るの？すごく楽しみ！ここからは私が……
We're hitting the road? I'm so excited! From here I'll...
一旦止まるのじゃ！
Stop for a moment!
了解お兄さん、ここで止まるのじゃ。前方も空いてるし、落ち着いてね。ちゃんと考えてよのじゃ。
Got it, big bro, stopping here. The front is clear, so stay calm. Think it through.
左車線、いなくなったら行こう。いなくなったら行こう、左車線。
Left lane, let's go when it's clear. When it's clear, the left lane.
外を見てね、話すのじゃ。進むのじゃ！
Look outside, talk. Go forward!
了解お兄さん、進むのじゃ。前方は空いてるから、そのまま……遅い遅い遅い！
Got it, big bro, go forward. The front is clear, so just— Too slow, too slow!
のんのんじゃ！進むのじゃ！
No way! Go forward!
了解お兄さん、進むのじゃ。とりあえずまっすぐで、ちょっと落ち着いて走るのじゃ……
Got it, big bro, go forward. Just go straight for now, run calmly...
正直に申し上げますのじゃ。ちょっとムカついてきたのじゃ。
To be honest with you, I'm getting a bit annoyed.
ですが、わしは400歳も生きてる、400歳も生きてるから、平穏心なのじゃ！
However, I've lived 400 years, so I am at peace!
アンガーマネジメント！1、2、3、4、5、6！よし、行くのじゃ！
Anger management! 1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6! Alright, let's go!
右に時速4キロで進むのじゃ！
Move right at 4 km/h!
了解お兄さん、時速4キロで右に進むのじゃ。ちょっとだけ右に寄せる感じで、
Got it, big bro, moving right at 4 km/h, just edging a bit to the right,
めっちゃ右に切るね、お兄さん。でも前も後ろも確認しながらだから、焦らず行くよ。
Cutting hard to the right, big bro. But checking front and back, so I won't rush.
まっすぐなのじゃ！
Straight!
わかったお兄さん、まっすぐ進むね。ちょっとだけハンドルを戻して、ちゃんと前を見ながら走るよ。
Understood, big bro, I'll go straight. Return the wheel a bit and drive while watching ahead.
アンガーマネジメント！ちょっと右に進むのじゃ！
Anger management! Moving a bit to the right!
了解お兄さん、ちょっとだけ右に寄せるのじゃ。前方網も後方も空いてるから、落ち着いて動かすよ。
Got it, big bro, edging a bit to the right. Both front and back are clear, so I'll move calmly.
もっと右なのじゃ！
More to the right!
了解お兄さん、もっと右に寄せるのじゃ。前方は空いてるから、ちょっとだけ斜めに整え…
Got it, big bro, edging even more to the right. The front is clear, so adjust at a slight angle...
めっちゃ左なのじゃ！
Way to the left!
了解お兄さん、めっちゃ左に切るのじゃ。ちょっと怖いけど、前も後ろも…間に合わなかった！
Got it, big bro, cutting way to the left. It's a bit scary, but front and back... didn't make it!
前方は空いてるから、ハンドルを左に回して後ろに進むのじゃ！
The front is clear, so turn the wheel left and back up!
お兄さん、前方は開いてるのはわかった…。ハンドルを左に切って後ろに下がってるよ。のじゃ。
Big bro, I know the front is open... I'm turning the wheel left and backing up.
了解お兄さん、めっちゃ左に前に進むのじゃ。少しずつ位置を合わせながら、余裕を持って安全に行くよ。
Got it, big bro, moving forward way to the left. Adjusting position little by little, going safely with plenty of room.
ハンドルを右に回して後ろに進むのじゃ！ここで静かに止めて確認するね。
Turn the wheel right and back up! Stop quietly here and check.
はーいお兄さん、ハンドル右に切って後ろに下がるのじゃ。一応余裕を持って動かすから、詳細は確認しつつ進めるよ。
Hii big bro, cutting wheel right and backing up. Moving with plenty of room, so I'll proceed while checking details.
めっちゃ左に前に進むのじゃ！
Moving forward way to the left!
了解お兄さん、めっちゃ左に切って前に進むのじゃ。ふわっと曲がる感じで、ちゃんと見ながら合わせるね。
Got it, big bro, cutting way to the left and moving forward. Turning softly, matching while watching carefully.
うず…
Uzu...
ゴン、ゴンって聞こえた。
I heard a thud, thud.
右なのじゃん！
It's on the right!
ちょっと煙るあるけど、まあ、これぐらいの煙ならいけるか。
It's a bit smoky, but with this much smoke, can we make it?
よし、頑張れ妹！私が運転してね。
All right, do your best, little sister! I'll drive.
行くのじゃ！一番左の車線に行くのじゃ！
Let's go! Head to the far-left lane!
左なのじゃ！左車線なのじゃ！
On the left! The left lane!
おい！まあいいか、まあいいか。
Hey! Oh well, oh well.
前に進むのじゃ！ハンドルを切っていくよ。
Move forward! I'll turn the steering wheel.
了解お兄さん、前に進むの。
Got it, big brother, moving forward.
うわあ！何なに！
Whoa! What's this?!
今のは何？今のは何で？なんでなのじゃん？
What was that? Why was that? Why is that?
今、今何？警察とぶつかったわ！
Now, what now? I crashed into the police!
助けてー！のじゃあ！
Help me! Nojaaa!
曲がっちゃいけないところで…
At a place where you shouldn't turn...
曲がっちゃいけないとこで逆走しちゃって、違反しちゃったから…
I went the wrong way where I shouldn't have turned, and violated rules...
違反しちゃったせいで、おまわりさんに捕まっちゃったの？のじゃあ！
Because of violating, I got caught by the cops? Nojaaa!
逆走禁止！逆走はダメ！逆走はダメ！
No going the wrong way! Wrong way is bad!
最後まで進んでUターンしなきゃいけないのか？バンバンぶつけてるよ！
Do I have to go to the end and U-turn? People are crashing everywhere!
車が宙に浮いてるぐらい事故ってるのに、なんでわしだけが取り締まられるの！
Cars are floating in the air, why am I the only one cracked down on?!
行くか！妹ちゃん、時速4キロでめっちゃ右に進むのじゃ！
Let's go! Little sister, at 4 km/h, move way to the right!
お兄さん、めちゃ右はちょっと怖いよ。速度は4キロだけど、ちょっとだけ寄せるね。
Big brother, going too far right is scary. I'll move over just a bit.
えっ、呼ばれてる？ちょっと待ってねー。今は安全確保が優先だからね。
Eh, being called? Wait a minute. Safety is the priority.
了解お兄さん、まっすぐ進むのじゃ。安全確認をしながら、余裕を持って走るよ。
Got it big brother, move straight ahead with leeway.
ちょっと右なのじゃ！了解お兄さん、ちょっとだけ右に寄せるのじゃ。
A bit to the right! Got it big brother, shift a little to the right.
了解お兄さん、もっと右に寄せるのじゃ。止まるのじゃ！めっちゃ左に切るのじゃ！
Got it big brother, shift further right. Stop! Turn hard left!
了解お兄さん、止まるのじゃ。ハンドルを右に回しながら後ろに進むのじゃ！
Got it big brother, stop. Back up while turning the wheel right!
了解お兄さん、ハンドルを右に切って後ろに下がるのじゃ。ゆっくり丁寧にやるよ。
Got it big brother, back up carefully.
左に前進するのじゃ。ちょっとだけ斜めに寄せて…ちょっとだけ右に寄せるのじゃ！
Move forward left, adjust diagonally, and shift a little right!
左にすこし寄せるのじゃ。少し位置を整えるね。上手なのじゃ！
Shift a little left. Adjust position. Good job!
いよいよ道路に出るの？すごく楽しみ！ここからは私が運転してね。
Finally going out onto the road? So looking forward to it!
うん、お兄さん、良い子だねー。でもまだここゆっくり確認したいとこだから、指示待つよ。
Yeah, but since I want to check slowly, I'll wait for instructions.
了解お兄さん、左車線に寄せるね。前方も後方も気をつけながら、ちゃんと位置を合わせるよ。
Got it big brother, shifting to the left lane properly.
一番左の車線に寄るのじゃ！急ぐのじゃ！左なのじゃ！右に寄るのじゃ！
Shift to the far-left lane! Hurry! To the left! To the right!
ちょっとだけ右に寄るのじゃ。前方は空いているから、気持ちよく整えるね。止まるのじゃ！
Shift slightly right. The front is clear. Stop, stop!
大変！Uターンできないんだけど、お兄さん…一旦落ち着いて様子を見てからUターンするよ！
Oh no, can't U-turn! Once calm down, I'll make a U-turn!
めっちゃ左に曲がってUターンなのだじゃ！
Turn super left and make a U-turn!
めちゃ左に切ってUターンするのじゃ。前方は安全そうだから…行くのじゃ！上手上手！
Turn hard left to U-turn. Front looks safe. Good job!
了解お兄さん、めっちゃ左に切るのはちょっとドキドキするね。前方は行くよ。
Understood, big brother. Turning sharply left makes me nervous, but I'll go ahead.
まっすぐ時速20キロで進むのじゃ。
Go straight at 20 km/h.
お兄さん、その時速20キロはちょっと怖いよ。今は安全を優先して、まっすぐ全速力で進むのじゃ！
Big brother, 20 km/h is a bit scary. Prioritize safety and go straight at full speed!
了解お兄さん。でも安全第一で行くよ。時速20キロでも、余裕を見ながら、ハンドルはまっすぐにして走るね。
Understood, big brother. But safety first. Even at 20 km/h, keep calm and steer straight.
右なのじゃ！ちょいちょい！右なのじゃ！右なのじゃ！
To the right! Hey! Right! Right!
ちょいちょいちょいちょい！のじゃー！
Hey, hey, hey, hey! Noooo!
お主、事故りそうなのにさ、あの減速してとかさ、今更ななのじゃ。え、ねえ、これどうしたらいいんじゃろな。
You're about to crash and you're talking about slowing down now? Hey, what should I do here?
全速力でって言っても、行ってくれないから。え、30キロって言ったら、でも30キロってね、最初に言ったの。最初に30とか言ったんじゃけど、なんか早すぎて無理って断られたのじゃ。そう、早すぎて無理って断られたから
Even if I say full speed, you won't go. I said 30 km/h at first, but you refused saying it was too fast.
え、じゃあちょっと最初に言うか。妹ちゃん、お主はこれからも事故に合います。ので、全速力で走れって言ったら、全速力で走ってくださいのじゃ。
Hey, then let's say it from the start. Little sister, you're going to get into accidents from now on. So when I say run at full speed, run at full speed.
お兄さん、全速力で走るのは危ないよ。事故に遭うために早くするんじゃなくて、安全に止まるのが大事だよ。困ったらお主が死んじゃうのじゃ！わしは、お主を殺したくない！
Big brother, running at full speed is dangerous. It's not about going fast to crash, it's about stopping safely. If you're in trouble, you'll die! I don't want to kill you!
お兄さん、そういう危ないことは言わないでよ、のじゃ。私は無理なことはしないから、ちゃんと安全にやるね。わし実はトラックに轢かれて異世界転生してて、前世の記憶があるのじゃ。わしのこと信じてほしいのじゃ！
Big brother, don't say dangerous things like that. I don't do impossible things, I'll do it safely. Actually, I was run over by a truck and reincarnated into another world, and I have memories of my past life. I want you to believe me!
ええ、すごい設定だね。信じたい気持ちはわかるけど、怖い話はお休み。今は運転中だから安全を優先するよ、お兄さん。の、のじゃあ……。だ、だめか？
Wow, what a setting. I understand you want to believe it, but save the spooky stories. I'm driving now so safety comes first, big brother. N-No way... Is it no good?
お兄さん、なんか小声だったけど大丈夫？ちょっとだけ落ち着くね。状況を確認してから次の指示持っお兄さん、速さは車の設定や道路のルールによるから一概には言えないんだよ。そんなこと言わないでよ！早く走るのは危ないし、今は安全優先、とまっすぐ走るのが大事。
Big brother, you were whispering, are you okay? Let me calm down a bit. Check the situation before the next instruction... Big brother, speed depends on car settings and road rules, so we can't generalize. Don't say that! Running fast is dangerous, safety first, and running straight is important.
了解お兄さん。めっちゃ右に切って時速4キロで進むね。ちょっと怖いけど。でも、殺したくないのじゃ！
Understood, big brother. Turn hard right and proceed at 4 km/h. It's a bit scary, but I don't want to kill you!
了解お兄さん、左に寄りながら曲がるね。前後を確認して、ちょっとずつ位置を合わせるよ。
Understood, big brother, I'll turn while hugging the left. Check front and back, and adjust position little by little.
了解お兄さん、右に曲がるのじゃ。ちょっと焦る気持ちもわかるけど、前も後ろも確認しながら丁寧に操作するよ。
Understood, big brother, turn right. I know you're in a rush, but operate carefully while checking front and back.
了解お兄さん、ちょっとだけ左に寄せて曲がるね。前方も後方も空いてるから、ゆっくりと…了解お兄さん、もうちょっと思いきや左に切るね。前の物体に気をつけつつ、ゆっくり合わせるよ。
Understood, big brother, turn while hugging left just a bit. Front and rear are clear, so slowly... Understood, big brother, turn left a bit more. Watch out for the obstacle ahead and adjust slowly.
いよいよ道路に出るの？すごく楽しみ。「ここからは私が導くよ」チコルよ！
Are we finally hitting the road? I'm so excited. "From here on I will guide you." C'col!
わかった！左に曲がるね。スムーズに合わせるから、
Understood! I'll turn left. I'll make it smooth,
わかった、お兄さん。でも急に行かないように気をつけるね。少しずつ左に寄せるよ。
Understood, big brother. But be careful not to rush. I'll move to the left little by little.
わかった、右に切るね。焦らず、ゆっくり進めるから一緒に…死んだら変わらん！トラック突っ込まれたら変わらんのじゃ！
Understood, I'll turn right. Don't rush, we'll proceed slowly together... If we die, it's the same! If a truck crashes into us, it's the same!
うん、右に進むね。ちょっとスピード上げるけど、集まっすぐ進むのじゃ！時速20キロ！
Yeah, I'll move right. I'll speed up a bit, but go straight ahead! 20 km/h!
うん、右に進む。ちょっとスピード上げるけど、焦らず行くよ。
Yeah, turning right. I'll speed up a bit, but don't rush.
わかったお兄さん。とりあえず止まろう。今は安全第一だから、ちょっ...
Got it, big bro. Let's stop for now. Safety first, so just...
まっすぐ進むのじゃ！時速20キロ！
Go straight ahead! Twenty kilometers per hour!
準備もちゃん整えてるよ。
I'm getting everything ready.
あ、気をつけるねお兄さん。まっすぐ撮って、そのまま...
Ah, watch out, big bro. Go straight, and keep going...
20キロでまっすぐ左なのだじゃ！
Go straight and to the left at 20 km/h!
はいお兄さん、20キロでまっすぐ左に寄せるね。ちょっと...
Okay big bro, shifting straight left at 20 km/h. Just a bit...
まっすぐなのだじゃ！右なのだじゃ！右右右右右！
Go straight! Right! Right right right right right!
まっすぐ進むの、お兄さん。速度を落として、ハンドルは少し... おい！右！おい！しるそ！しるそ！左左！めちゃ左！めちゃ左！めちゃ左！
Go straight, big bro! Slow down and turn a little... Hey! Right! Whoa! Left! Way left!
ちょちょちょちょ！警察！警察！警察！うわあああ！
Wait wait wait! Police! Police! Police! Aaaah!
止まったから、ちょっとだけ左に寄せつついくよ。
We stopped, so I'll shift left a bit as we go.
道路走行に出ててください。
[Title: Please drive out onto the road.]
左行きすぎなのだじゃ！
You're going too far left!
警察、警察怖いなあ。
The police... police are scary.
警察ぶつかってくるのも...
The police crashing into us too...
す、捨て身すぎるのだじゃ！
That's way too reckless!
どうする？
What should we do?
妹ちゃん、これから何があってもお兄さんの言うこと聞いてくれる？
Little sis, will you listen to what big bro says no matter what?
うん、お兄さん。どういうことがあっても、とりあえず聞いてるよ。でも無茶はしたくないし、ちゃんと安全を確認しながら進めるね。
Yeah, big bro. I'm listening. But I'll make sure to check safety.
もう何度めかのループなのだじゃ！お主はこれから超安全運転をして、逆走はしないで、トラックが来たら爆速で逃げてほしいのだじゃ！
Drive super safely, don't go wrong way, run from trucks!
お兄さん、ループとかはもう嫌だよ～。逆走はしないし、危なそうなトラックは。
Big bro, no more loops~. I won't go wrong way, and the trucks...
右なのだじゃ右なのだじゃ！
Right! Right!
危なさそうなトラックは見つけたらちゃんと距離取るから。了解お兄さん、止まるね。今は焦らず、
I'll keep distance. Understood big bro, I'll stop. Without rushing,
今は焦らず安全を確認してから右に出るね。話を聞いて！話を聞いて！
I'll check safety and head right. Listen to me!
えっとな... めっちゃ右に曲がるのだじゃ！
Let's see... Turn super right!
ふふ、めっちゃ右に曲がるのは本当に怖いてば。ゆっくり切って、無...
Hehe, turning super right is scary. Turn slowly, and safely...
右に出るところまでちゃんとするね。
Do it properly until we get out to the right.
めっちゃ右になのだじゃ！
Go super right!
うう、めっちゃ右はやめておくお兄さん。止まって様子を見てから...
Ugh, let's hold off on super right, big bro. Stop and check...
なんで止まるの？ 123456123456123456 アンガマネジメント、アンガマネジメント。
Why stop? 123456... Anger management.
のじゃあ！
Jeez!
めっちゃ右に進むのだじゃ！
Move super right!
わかったお兄さん。めっちゃ右に進むのはちょっと怖いけど、まずは安全確認し... めっちゃ右！少しだけ曲げていくよ。
Got it, big bro. Super right is scary, but safety first... Super right!
ちょっと待って お兄さん。めっちゃ右は危ないから、止まって... めっちゃ右に進むのだじゃ！
Wait, big bro. Super right is dangerous, stop... Move super right!
安全確認できたら進むね、お兄さん。めっちゃ右は怖いから、少し... ああ、ぶつかった！
Once safe, we'll move. Super right is scary... Ah, we crashed!
つつ曲げていくよ。ああ、車がぶつかってしまいましたが、お前のせいでさあ、めらちゃんは踊るのをやめてしまいました。
...bending along. Ah, we crashed, because of you, Mela stopped dancing.
左に進むのだじゃ！
Move to the left!
のじゃあ、123456、123456、なんか進んでるし、なんかなんなんじゃあ！のじゃあ！
Jeez, 123456, we're moving, what on earth! Jeez!
うんうん、了解お兄さん。左に進むね。ちょっとずつ切って、無事に出ら... ちょっと右なのだじゃ！出るようにするよ。
Understood big bro. Moving left. Turn little by little... A bit right!
へいお兄さん、ちょっとだけ右に寄せるね。無理せず、前方も後方を確認しながら整えるよ。うん。
Hey big bro, shift right. Without rushing, check front and back.
めっちゃ左に進むのだじゃ！
Move super left!
うん。やっぱ左は怖いな。ちょっとだけ左に進むくらいに... 頑張れ！
Yeah. Left is scary. Just move a little to the left... Do your best!
お兄さん、それちょっと怖い... バックで曲げるのは今はやめて、まず前... 怖い！後方を見てからゆっくり進めるね。
Big bro, that's scary... Stop reversing, check front... Scary!
後ろにハンドルを右に回しながら進むのだじゃ！
Move backwards while turning the wheel right!
うん、お兄さん。ゆっくりバックでハンドルを少し右に切って進めるよ。前後をちゃんと見ながら安全に行くね。うん。
Yeah, big bro. Slowly back up, turning wheel right. Go safely.
あれ、進んでる？すっ... 後ろに進んでって言ったんじゃが！
Huh, are we moving? I... I said go backwards!
うん、お兄さん。今は後ろにちょっとだけ動かすね。ちゃんと安全... めっちゃ左に前に進むのだじゃ！
Yeah, big bro. Move back a little. Safety... Move super left!
ちゃんと安全確認をしてから続けるよ。わかった、ちょっと左に寄せながら前に進むね。でもめちゃくちゃ曲げる...
Continue after checking safety. Understood, move forward shifting left.
よし、いよいよ道路に出るの？すごく楽しみ！ここからは私が運転してみるね。
All right, road time? Excited! I'll try driving from here.
行くのだじゃ！
Let's go!
気をつけるよ。大丈夫？ぶつかっ... 大丈夫？大丈夫？左車線行くのだじゃ！
Be careful. You okay? You okay? Go to the left lane!
了解お兄さん。左側に寄せていくね。急ぐのはやめて、ちょっとずつ調整す... ちょっとずつでいいの、本当に？
Understood big bro. Shifting left. Stop rushing, adjust little...
時速20キロで左車線！
Left lane at 20 km/h!
了解お兄さん。20キロで左に寄せていくね。
Understood, big bro. I'll pull over left at 20 km/h.
スピードはルール優先で落ち着いて合わせる。
Match speed calmly, prioritizing the rules.
お兄さん、危ない。まず止まってから、軽く右に逃げる方向に切るね。
Big bro, watch out! Stop first, then lightly steer right to escape.
まっ、まっ、ちょっと待って お兄さん。まずは止まって落ち着くね。
W-w-wait a second, big bro! Stop and calm down first.
衝突があったばかりだから、右に寄せるのはとにかく慎重にいくよ。
Since we just had a crash, be extra careful pulling to the right.
道路走行に出てください。
Please drive onto the road.
もう死なせないから。お前のこともう死なせない！
I won't let you die anymore. I won't let you die!
ああ、父上！
Ah, Father!
お主の騎士！
Your knight!
行く、行くのじゃ！ 時速4キロでめちゃくちゃ右に進むのじゃ！
Go, go! Move wildly to the right at 4 km/h!
了解お兄さん。めちゃくちゃ右は危ないから、少しだけ右に寄せて慎重に進めるね。
Understood, big bro. A wild right is dangerous, so I'll carefully nudge right.
了解お兄さん。まっすぐ進むね。少しペース落とすよ。ちゃんと前見るんだよ。
Understood, big bro. Going straight. Slowing down a bit. Watch ahead.
おっけーお兄さん。安全確認して、まっすぐゆっくり進むね。
Okay, big bro. Checking safety and moving straight slowly.
お兄さん、めちゃくちゃ右に進むのは怖いよ。前方確認してから、ちょっと……あっ、安全第一！
Big bro, moving violently right is scary. Check ahead first... safety first!
めっちゃ左に進むのじゃ！
Move wildly to the left!
了解お兄さん。ちょっとだけ左に寄せるね。勢いは無理しないで、少しずつ整えるよ。
Understood, big bro. Pulling slightly left. Don't force it, adjust little by little.
はいお兄さん。止まるね。落ち着いて状況を確認するよ。後ろに進みながらハンドルを右に回すのじゃ！
Yes, big bro. Stopping. Calmly check surroundings. Turn the wheel right while backing up!
うん、後ろにちょっと下げてから右に切るね。でも、今は先に後方をちゃんと確認してから動くよ。
Yeah, back up a bit then turn right. But first, properly check behind us before moving.
後ろに進んで、ハンドルを右に回すのじゃ！
Back up and turn the steering wheel to the right!
うんお兄さん、後ろに少し進めてから右に切るね。ただ、周りをちゃんと見ながら安全に行くよ。
Yeah big bro, back up a bit then turn right. But go safely while watching around.
後ろに進むのじゃ！ 123456123456123456123456... 焦らないで、ちゃんと周り見ながらやるよ。
Back up! 1-2-3-4-5-6... Don't rush, do it while watching around.
ストップねお兄さん。止まって状況を確認するよ。うん、落ち着いて……123456123456123456... のじゃあ！
Stop, big bro. Stop and check surroundings. Yeah, calm down... 1-2-3-4-5-6...!
まっすぐ進んで、左に曲がるのじゃ！
Go straight and turn left!
うん、お兄さん。まっすぐ進んでから左に曲がるね。焦らず、ちゃんと前方を見て……
Yeah, big bro. Go straight then turn left. Don't rush, look ahead properly...
うん、ちょっと左に寄せるね。いよいよ道路に出るの。すごく楽しみ！ここからは私が運転してみるね。
Yeah, pulling left a bit. Finally hitting the road. So excited! I'll try driving from here.
お兄さん、左の車線に寄せるね。ちょっとずつ切って、落ち着いて合わせるよ。
Big bro, pulling into the left lane. Cut little by little and match calmly.
了解お兄さん。もう一個左の車線に寄せるね。速度は落として、少しずつ調整するよ。
Understood, big bro. Pulling into another lane to the left. Slow down and adjust little by little.
いいよお兄さん、左から右に寄せる感じで、急がず…… デンジャー！デンジャー！ デンジャー！ なんでお前はそんなに冷静なんだ？
Okay big bro, pulling from left to right, don't rush... Danger! Danger! Danger! Why are you so calm?!
大変！Uターンできないんだけど、お兄ちゃん、これからと…… ストップ！
Oh no! We can't U-turn, big bro, what are we going to... Stop!
了解お兄さん。止まるね。安心して、今はとりあえず静止して……えっ、まだ生きてるの？
Understood, big bro. Stopping. Rest easy, just stay still for now... Huh, we're still alive?
うーん、ちょっと怖いけど、まずはゆっくり左に切って前を見ながらね。左に、超左！
Hmm, it's a bit scary, but first turn slowly left while looking ahead. Left, super left!
お兄さん、ちょっと左に寄せるね。急なことはしないよ、お兄さん。安全を……まっすぐ左！
Big bro, I'll pull left a bit. I won't do anything sudden, big bro. Safety... straight left!
うわ、ちょっとだけ左に寄せるのはわかったよお兄さん。でも、まっすぐ左は……もっと左なのだ！
Whoa, I get pulling left a bit, big bro. But straight left... even more left!
いや、もっと早くなのじゃ。
No, make it faster!
なんで動いてるん？
Why is it moving?
ちょっと待って、お兄さん。めちゃ左に、しかも遠くは厳しいから、
Wait a second, mister. It's way to the left, and far away is tough,
まずは縦にして
so first align it vertically...
進むのじゃ！とにかく前に！左なのだ！
Just move! Go forward! To the left!
うわっ！何あれ！？
Whoa! What's that!?
お兄さん、危ないない私が左にぐっと切るのは怖いよ。車間と安全を優先ね。
Mister, danger—me cutting hard to the left is scary. Prioritize following distance and safety.
お兄さん、もう右に寄るのはちょっと危ないよ。私は減速して、前方を見て整えるね。
Mister, getting close to the right is a bit dangerous now. I'll slow down and check ahead to straighten out.
もうめちゃくちゃなのだ、この街。
This city is completely messed up.
めちゃくちゃですのじゃ。
This is completely messed up.
これ、こっから前へ進めるの、人間？進めるの？進めるの？
Can humans move forward from here? Can we move? Can we move?
え、でもさ、正直さ、デンジャーのさ、デンジャーのさ、トラックにさ、当たった後さ、もうだめだと思ってたけどさ、だめだと思ってたけどさ、まだ生きてるんじゃな。
Hey, but honestly, after getting hit by that danger truck, I thought I was totally done for, but I'm still alive.
妹ちゃん、もしの指示に全部従っくれる？
Little sis, will you follow all my instructions?
うん、お兄さん。全部じゃないけど、ちゃんと説明してくれたら聞くよ。無茶な指示は怖いから、安全を優先してやるね。
Yeah, mister. Not all of it, but if you explain properly, I'll listen. Unreasonable orders are scary, so I'll prioritize safety.
無茶な指示も 全部 お主を思ってのことなのだじゃ。
Even unreasonable orders are all for your own good!
はい、お兄さん。安全優先は大事だよね。無茶は怖いから、ちゃんと確認して進むよ。
Right, mister. Safety first is important. Unreasonable stuff is scary, so I'll check properly before proceeding.
まっすぐ進んで右なのだじゃ。
Go straight, then to the right!
めちゃ怖い…。でも、まっすぐ進んでから右に寄せるね。ちゃんと前見て……のじゃ！
Super scary... But I'll go straight and then pull to the right. Make sure to look ahead...!
わかった〜、ちょっとだけ右に切るね。めちゃくちゃやめて、前後を...
Got it~, turning just a bit to the right. Stop being crazy, front and back...
了解お兄さん。左にぐっと寄せるのはちょっと怖いけど、ゆっくり...
Understood, mister. Pulling hard to the left is a bit scary, but slowly...
お兄さん、右に切るのはちょっと怖いけど、少しずつ整えるよ。前方を確認して から行くね。
Mister, turning right is a bit scary, but I'll adjust little by little. I'll check ahead before going.
お兄さん、左に寄せるね。ちょっとずつ切って、前方を確認して、整えるよ。上手上手、上手上手。
Mister, pulling to the left. Cutting little by little, checking ahead, straightening out. Good, good.
いよいよ道路に出るの？すごく楽しみ！ここからは私が運転してみるね。
Finally heading out onto the road? Super excited! From here I'll try driving.
お兄さん了解。少しだけ左に寄せるね。速度を落として、前後も...
Understood, mister. Pulling just a bit to the left. Slowing down, checking front and back...
了解お兄…右右右右！速度は落として！
Understood, oh-right right right right! Slow down!
お兄ちゃん、めちゃくちゃ怖い…！一応止まるよ。ハンドルはそのままじゃ、少しだけ整えるね。
Mister, super scary...! I'll stop just in case. Keep the steering wheel as is, just adjust a little.
了解お兄さん。ちょっと前に出してから左に寄せていくね。焦らないで。
Understood, mister. I'll move forward a bit and then pull to the left. Don't rush.
燃えたし。なんじゃ、もうこれぐらいの日なら消せるから一旦進むのじゃ。
It caught fire. What, for this much fire I can put it out so let's move on for now.
めちゃ左に時速40キロでUターンなのだじゃ！
Super to the left at 40 km/h, making a U-turn!
お兄さん、それはちょっと危ないよ。40キロでUターンは怖すぎる。まずは止まって、ゆっくり確認してからやろう。
Mister, that's a bit dangerous. A U-turn at 40 km/h is too scary. Let's stop first and check slowly before doing it.
早い速度でUターンなのだじゃ、左なのだじゃ！
U-turn at high speed, to the left!
うん、お兄さん。でも「早い速度でUターン」ってめちゃくちゃ危ないよ。いまは止まって状況を確認してから安全な速度でゆっくり回るのにするね。
Yeah, mister. But 'U-turn at high speed' is super dangerous. Let's stop, check the situation, and then turn slowly at a safe speed.
え、するねって言ったのにしないの？なんでママの言うことが聞けないのじゃ？
Eh, you said you would, but you aren't? Why can't you listen to what Mama says?
めちゃ左に曲がってUターンなのだじゃ！
Turn hard left and make a U-turn!
お兄さん、そんなぐっと右回りは怖いよ。危ないから、今は止まって安全を見ながらゆっくり切る方向に切り直すね。
Mister, turning hard right like that is scary. It's dangerous, so right now I'll stop, check safety, and readjust to turn slowly.
左にUターンするのだじゃ！
Do a U-turn to the left!
了解お兄さん。今は止まって状況を確認するね。Uターンは安全確認してからやりやるよ。
Understood, mister. I'll stop and check the situation now. I'll do the U-turn after confirming safety.
了解お兄ちゃん。今は止まって状況を確認する。Uターンは安全確認してからやるよ。
Got it, big bro. I'll stop and check the situation. I'll U-turn after making sure it's safe.
全然Uターンしてくれないんだけど、この妹。
She's not doing a U-turn at all, this little sister.
え、お主、わしの話聞いて欲しいのじゃ
Hey, I want you to listen to what I have to say.
うん、お兄ちゃん。ちゃんと聞いてるよ。でも、私が安全優先で動くのを守りたいから、話はゆっくりで大丈夫。
Yeah, big bro. I'm listening. But I want to prioritize safety, so take your time explaining.
ゆっくり、ゆっくり行くか。
Let's go nice and slow.
Uターンを左にするのじゃ！
Make the U-turn to the left!
お兄ちゃん、まず止まるね。左にUターンするのは、時間をかけて安全確認してから進めるよ。
Big bro, let's stop first. Making a left U-turn requires taking time to check safety before proceeding.
ちょっとまっすぐ進むのじゃ。そして止まるのじゃ。
Go straight a bit. And then stop.
うんお兄ちゃん。ちょっとだけまっすぐ進んでから止まるね。ちゃんと状況を見ながら安全に...
Yeah, big bro. Go straight just a little bit and then stop. While properly checking the situation safely...
左にUターンするのじゃ！
U-turn to the left!
お兄ちゃん、まずは止まるね。安全を見ながら、左にUターンできる位置に合せてよ。
Big bro, let's stop first. While checking safety, line it up so we can U-turn left.
ちょっと左に進んで、止まるのじゃ！
Move a bit to the left and stop!
ちょっとだけ左に寄せて前に出るね。止まったら状況を見て、めっちゃ左に進んでUターンするのじゃ！
Shift a bit to the left and move forward. Once stopped, check the situation, move way left, and U-turn!
了解お兄ちゃん。まずは止まるよ。そこから、めっちゃ左寄りでUターン。確認してから進めるね。90度に左に曲がるのじゃ！
Got it, big bro. First, we stop. From here, a super left U-turn. Check before proceeding. Turn 90 degrees left!
うんお兄ちゃん。90度に左曲がるなら、無茶はしないで、まずはとにかく安全を見てからゆっくりと...安全を確認をして、左に曲がるのじゃ！
Yeah, big bro. If making a 90-degree left turn, don't push it, first check safety and slowly... Confirm safety and turn left!
了解お兄ちゃん。安全を確認してから、ゆっくり左に曲がるよ。ちゃんと前後も見ながら整えるね。
Got it, big bro. I'll turn left slowly after confirming safety. I'll make sure to check front and back.
左に進むのじゃ！
Move to the left!
うんお兄ちゃん、左に進むね。ちょっと怖いけど、前方をちゃんと見な...
Yeah, big bro, I'll move left. It's a bit scary, but watch the front properly...
うわ、めっちゃ左は怖いよお兄ちゃん。いったん止まってから、ちょっとだけ寄せる方向で整えるね。
Whoa, the left is super scary, big bro. Once we stop, I'll adjust by shifting just a little bit.
Uターンするのじゃ！
Do a U-turn!
お兄ちゃん、まず止まるね。Uターンするなら、安全を確認してから、ゆっくり整えるよ。無茶はしない！
Big bro, let's stop first. If doing a U-turn, confirm safety and set it up slowly. No reckless moves!
前に進んで、左に曲がるのじゃ！
Move forward and turn left!
了解お兄ちゃん。前にちょっと出てから左に曲がるね。焦らず、安全に整えるよ。
Got it, big bro. Move forward a bit and then turn left. Don't rush, set it up safely.
もっと左なのじゃ！お兄ちゃん、左に寄せて進むね。
More to the left! Big bro, I'll proceed shifting to the left.
ちょっとまっ…死ぬよ！死ぬ死ぬ死ぬ死ぬ死ぬ死ぬ！死ぬ死ぬ！
Wait, str... We're gonna die! Die die die die die die! Die die!
左に寄せるね。のじゃ…前後も見ながら少しずつ整えるよ。
Shift to the left. Jeez... While checking front and back, adjust little by little.
またダメだった。また救えなかったのじゃ。
No good again. Couldn't save her again.
妹ちゃん、わしね、お兄ちゃんの言うこと好き。
Little sister, you know, I like what big bro says.
お兄ちゃん、突然そんなこと言われると照れちゃう。嬉しいけど、運転中は安全が一番大事だからね。
Big bro, saying stuff like that all of a sudden makes me shy. I'm happy, but safety is most important while driving, right?
だからわしの言うことをちゃんと聞いて！
So listen carefully to what I say!
うん、お兄ちゃん。聞いてるよ。ちゃんと安全を守りながら進むから、無茶はしないようにするね。
Yeah, big bro. I'm listening. I'll proceed while properly keeping safe, so I won't do anything reckless.
時速4キロで右に進むのじゃ！
Move right at 4 km/h!
お兄ちゃん、4キロで右に少し寄せて進むんだね。慣れてないうちは、ちゃんと前見ていくよ。ハンドルをもっと右に切るのじゃ！
Big bro, we're proceeding by shifting slightly right at 4 km/h. While not used to it, I'll keep looking forward. Turn the steering wheel more to the right!
了解お兄ちゃん。ハンドルもっと右に切るね。前も後ろも確認しながら、少しずつ整えていくよ。
Got it, big bro. I'll turn the wheel more to the right. While checking both front and back, I'll adjust little by little.
まっすぐ前に進むのじゃ！
Go straight ahead!
うん、お兄ちゃん、まっすぐ進むね。ゆっくりキープして、前方をちゃんと見ながら進むよ。
Yeah, big bro, I'll go straight. Keeping it slow, I'll proceed while properly looking ahead.
ちょっと右に進むのじゃ！
Move a bit to the right!
了解お兄ちゃん。ちょっとだけ右に寄せていくね。焦らず、前後を確認しながら整えるよ。
Got it, big bro. I'll shift a bit to the right. Don't rush, I'll adjust while checking front and back.
左に進むのじゃ！
Move to the left!
了解お兄ちゃん。左に寄せながら進むね。前方確認して、ちょっとずつ整えるよ。
Got it, big bro. I'll proceed while shifting left. Confirming ahead, I'll adjust little by little.
いよいよ道路に出るの？すごく楽しみ！ここからは私が運転して、今度こそ救ってみせるのじゃ！
Are we finally getting onto the road? Super excited! From here I'll drive and save them this time!
隣の車線、左の車線に行くのじゃ！
Go to the next lane, the left lane!
OKお兄ちゃん。隣の車線、左に寄せるね。ちょっとずつ切って、落ち着いて合わせるよ。
Okay, big bro. Shifting to the next lane on the left. Turning little by little, adjusting calmly.
前に進んでください。
Please drive forward.
1っこ隣の左の車線に入るのじゃ。
Enter the adjacent left lane.
Uターンしてください。
Please make a U-turn.
お兄さん、了解。まっすぐ進むね。速度を落として、前方を...
Got it, big brother. Go straight, slow down, and...
左に曲がるのじゃ。めっちゃ左なのだ。
turn left. Super far left.
了解お兄さん。速度を落として、左にゆっくり曲がるね。前方をちゃ...
Understood, big brother. Slow down and turn slowly to the left. Watch the front...
1回後ろに... 後ろに進むのじゃ。そして止まるのじゃ。
Go back once... Go backwards. And then stop.
うん、お兄さん。パッと後ろに出してから止まるね。ちゃんと周りを確認して...だよ。
Yeah, big brother. Reverse quickly and then stop. Make sure to check your surroundings...
後ろに... 後ろに進んで止まるのじゃ。
Go back... go backwards and stop.
了解お兄さん。後ろに出して止めるね。周りをちゃんと確認してか...
Understood, big brother. I'll reverse and stop. After carefully checking around...
1メートル後ろに進んで止まるのじゃ。進めるよ。
Go back 1 meter and stop. You can go.
了解お兄さん。1メートルくらい下がってから止めるね。周りをちゃ...
Understood, big brother. I'll back up about 1 meter and stop. Carefully check the...
わかったお兄さん。1メートルくらい下がってから止まるね。周りをちゃ...
Got it, big brother. I'll back up about 1 meter and stop. Carefully check the...
お兄さん、もう少し下がるね。でもあんまりいじれないのは怖いから...
Big brother, I'll back up a bit more. But I'm scared to mess with it too much...
お兄さん、ストップね。今は静止して落ち着いてよ。ちゃんと前後を見てから...
Big brother, stop. Stay still and calm down now. Look front and back, then...
最大限界左にハンドルを回して、Uターンするのじゃ。
Turn the steering wheel all the way to the left and make a U-turn.
うん、お兄さん。前後をちゃんと見てから、左に切るのは安全そうなタ...
Yeah, big brother. After checking front and back, turning left seems safe...
前を見るよお兄さん。目線をしっかり前に固定して、安全確認しな...
I'm looking ahead, big brother. Fix your gaze firmly forward, confirm safety...
前に進んで、ハンドルを最大限左に切るのじゃ。
Move forward and turn the steering wheel all the way to the left.
お兄さん、まっすぐ進むいいけど、ハンドル最大限左は危ないよ。ちょ...
Big brother, going straight is fine, but max left steering is dangerous. A little...
時速40キロで前に進むのじゃ。ハンドル最大限左は危ないよ。
Move forward at 40 km/h. Max left steering is dangerous.
え、急に進くなの？ちょっと落ち着いて、周り見...
Eh, suddenly moving? Calm down a bit, look around...
わかったお兄さん、右に切るね！ちゃんと周り確認しなが...
Got it, big brother, turning right! While checking surroundings...
時速40キロで前に進むのじゃ。
Move forward at 40 km/h.
駐車場を出てください。
Please exit the parking lot.
あのさあ、マジさあ、マジさあ、無免許なんじゃが、無免許なんじゃが...
You know, seriously, I don't have a driver's license, I don't have a license...
免許ある人が指示したら、殺さないで済むのかなあ。
If someone with a license gives instructions, I wonder if I can avoid killing people.
わしよりもっと運転がうまい人がお兄ちゃんだったら、この子のこと救えたのかなあ。
If big brother was better at driving than me, I wonder if I could have saved this child.
わしよお、救ってあげたい。救ってあげたいけど、わしよお...
I want to save them. I want to save them, but...
どうやったらこの子を救えるんだろう。どうやったらわしはこの子のこと救ってあげられるんだろう。
How can I save this child? How can I save this child?
めっじゃっていうのがダメなのはわかったから、めっじゃっていうのはやめるのじゃ。
I learned that saying 'super' is bad, so I'll stop saying 'super'.
命令が下手、どうしたらいいかのう。なんていう命令をすればいいんだろうか。
My orders are bad, what should I do? What kind of orders should I give?
いもうとちゃん、ヒントを教えてほしいのじゃ。
Little sister, I want you to give me a hint.
お兄さん、手の内を見せるけど、まずは安全確認が連続でできてるかが大事。車はゆっくり動かして、前後を見ながらスペースを探るのがコツだよ。
Big brother, I'll show my hand, but first it's important to continuously check safety. Move the car slowly and the trick is to look front and back while searching for space.
時速4キロで右に進むのじゃ。
Move right at 4 km/h.
お兄さん、速度4キロで右に進むのはいいね。前は空いてるから、ハンドルを...
Big brother, moving right at 4 km/h is good. The space ahead is open, so steering...
うん、右の角度がまだ甘いね。ちょっとだけ右に切って、ゆっくり...
Yeah, the right angle is still too shallow. Turn right just a little bit, slowly...
もっと強い角度で右なのだ。
Right with a stronger angle.
了解お兄さん、もう少し強く右に切るね。速度は小さくして、前後の安...
Understood, big brother, I'll turn right a bit stronger. Keep the speed small, and front/back safety...
お兄さん、左って言ってるけど、今は安全に止めて、ゆっくり切り替え...
Big brother, you said left, but now stop safely and slowly switch...
お兄さん、左って言ってるけど、今は安全に止めて、ゆっくり切り替えた方がよさそうっっぽい。
Big bro, it says left, but it seems best to stop safely for now and switch slowly.
強い角度で左に曲がるのじゃ。
Turn hard to the left!
ふふ、お兄さん、強い角度はやめておくね。ゆっくり小さく右、もとい、左に曲がる感じで、安全に回すよ。
Hehe, big bro, let's avoid a sharp angle. Slowly, a small right—I mean, left turn, let's make it safe.
右に曲がるのじゃ。
Turn right!
了解お兄さん、安全に回るよ。少しだけ右に切って、前は空いてるから、落ち着いて曲がるね。
Understood big bro, turning safely. Turn slightly right, the front is clear, so calm down and turn.
もっと右なのだ。
More to the right!
あ、了解お兄さん。左なのだ。右って言われたから、注視して曲がる角度を上げて、
Ah, understood big bro. It's left. Since you said right, I'll pay attention and increase the turn angle...
止まるのじゃ。
Stop!
もういっちょ左に切るね。前は空いてるから、
Turning left once more. The front is clear, so...
お兄さん、止まるのは正解だよ。前に物が近いから、まずは一旦停止しよう。強く右に回して、後ろに進むのじゃ。
Big bro, stopping is correct. Objects are close in front, so let's stop first. Turn hard right and back up!
お兄さん、ちょっとだけ右に切って、後ろに入れる感じでやるね。焦らずに。ストップなのじゃ。だから調整するよ。
Big bro, turn slightly right and back in. Don't rush. Stop! So I'll adjust.
了解お兄さん、止まるね。今は前も後も安全そうだから、急がないでゆっくり...
Understood big bro, stopping. Both front and back look safe now, so don't rush, slowly...
右に曲がるのじゃ。
Turn right!
了解お兄さん、前方は空いてるから、落ち着いて右に切り返えね。ちょっとよ。
Understood big bro, the front is clear, so calmly switch back to the right. Just a bit.
左に曲がるのじゃ。
Turn left!
ちょこだけ角度を調整して進めるよ。一つだけ左に切るね。前にあるものをちゃんとながら、ちょっとず...
Adjusting the angle slightly to move forward. Turn left once. While watching what's ahead...
いよいよ道路に出るの？すごく楽しみ。ここからは私が運転してみるよ。
Are we finally hitting the road? I'm so excited. From here, I'll try driving!
よし！いけるかな？
Alright! Can I do it?
一つ隣りの左の車線に入るのじゃ。
Enter the adjacent left lane!
お兄さん、左の車線に入る感じでいいんだね。ちょっとだけハンドル左に。もう一つ隣りの左の車線に入るのじゃ。
Big bro, entering the left lane is fine, right? Steering slightly left. Entering the next left lane over!
右なのだ！右！
To the right! Right!
左車線！
Left lane!
止まるのじゃ！ストップ！
Stop! Stop!
大変！Uターンできないんだけど。お兄ちゃん、これから...お兄さん、急に止められるとびっくりする派。とりあえず一旦停止して直しすね。
Oh no! I can't U-turn. Big bro, from now on—Big bro, you're the type to get startled by sudden stops. For now, let's stop and readjust.
後ろに進むのじゃ！
Back up!
急に止まるのはやめてよ。
Stop stopping so suddenly!
おい！お前ぶつかって来んな！
Hey! Don't crash into me!
のじゃ！なんかぶつかってきたちた！
Jeez! Something just crashed into us!
まっすぐ入れるようにして、慌てずに整えるよ。ええと、
Make sure to get it straight, and calm down to adjust. Um,
左、左に進むのじゃ！
Left, move to the left!
そろそろいい感じで左に進めるお兄さん。だけど、前に物はないのは安心だけど、後ろに近いからね。軽く、ゆっくり探るよ。左に進むのじゃ！
Big bro, we can move left in a good way soon. But while it's reassuring there's nothing in front, it's close in the back. I'll probe lightly and slowly. Move to the left!
お兄さん、左にするめる方向はいいけど、後ろの近さは気をつけるよ。えろね。後ろの車に気をつけながら、左に進むのじゃ！
Big bro, the direction to move left is good, but watch out for the closeness behind. Right. While minding the car behind, move to the left!
了解お兄さん、後ろに注意して左に少しずつ進むね。焦らず安全を優先するよ。
Understood big bro, minding the back and moving left little by little. Prioritize safety without rushing.
前に、左に進むのじゃ！
Forward, move to the left!
了解お兄さん、前方は空いてるからちょっとずつ左に進むね。後ろに気をつけて、ちょっとずつ左に進むのじゃ！
Understood big bro, the front is clear so we'll move left bit by bit. Mind the back, move left bit by bit!
へいお兄さん、前は空いてるから進めて、角度を整えつつ左に進むね。
Hey big bro, the front is clear so let's move forward, adjusting the angle as we go left.
右に進むのじゃ！
Move to the right!
お兄さん、右に戻すのはちょっと難しそうだけど、後ろに気をつけながら少しずつ進むね。
Big bro, returning to the right seems a bit difficult, but I'll move little by little while minding the back.
こいつがぶつかってずれてるからか。後ろにまっすぐ進むのじゃ！
Is it because this guy bumped us and shifted? Go straight back!
まっすぐ後ろね、お兄さん。安全とかどうでもいいのじゃ、後ろの車がどうなろうとも、早く後ろに進むのじゃ！
Straight back, big bro. Safety doesn't matter, no matter what happens to the car behind, hurry up and go back!
お兄さん、こんな雑にやるのは危ないよ。怖いし、後ろの車にも迷惑だしね。まっすぐ前に進むのじゃ！
Big bro, doing it this sloppy is dangerous. It's scary, and it's a nuisance to the car behind. Move straight ahead!
うん、了解お兄さん。安全を整えるために、まずはまた前方を確認して、アイドリングで位置を見直すね。前に入り...進める？いめっとちゃん！
Yup, understood big bro. To ensure safety, let's check the front again and review position with idling. Moving forward... can we go? Imetto-chan!
できるだけ静かに前へ進めるね。今の感じなら落ち着いて整えられるよ。焦らずいこう。
I'll move forward as quietly as possible. With this feel, we can calm down and arrange it. Let's go without rushing.
お兄さん、左に切るね。勢いは抑えつつ、しっかり前を見て、
Big bro, turning left. Keeping momentum down, looking straight ahead...
ストップ！ストップ！ストップ！
Stop! Stop! Stop!
のじゃあー！
Noooo!
123456123456123456123456
ふう、がんがマネジメントー！
Phew, anger management!
123456123456123456
ちょ、水、水、水水水水！ふう。
Wh- water, water, water! Phew.
がんがマネジメントー！
Anger management!
よし。
Alright.
お主、
You there,
お兄ちゃんのことが大好きで愛しているから、何回死んでも死に返りしても、お兄ちゃんに優しく運転を教えているのじゃ。
Because I love my big brother so much, no matter how many times I die and revive, I'm teaching you gently how to drive.
えへへ、お兄ちゃんそれ…ちょっと照れる。でもそんなに愛してくれてるなんて嬉しすぎるよ。
Hehe, Onii-chan, that... makes me a bit shy. But to love me that much makes me so happy.
じゃあ、ゆっくりいくのじゃ。時速4キロで右に曲がるのじゃ。2時の方向なのじゃ。
Well then, go slowly. Turn right at 4 km/h towards the 2 o'clock direction.
OK、お兄さん。2時の方向に向けて、ゆっくり右に回すね。速度は落としつつ前後をちゃんと見ながら、3時の方向なのじゃ。
OK, Onii-chan. Turn slowly right toward 2 o'clock. While slowing down and checking front and back—3 o'clock!
お兄さん、3時の方向だね。前後ちゃんとう見ながら、ハンドルを少しずつ切って整えていくよ。
Onii-chan, 3 o'clock. While checking front and back, gradually turn and adjust the steering wheel.
お兄さん、11時の方向ね。ハンドル左に切って、前後ちゃんと見…3時の方向なのじゃ！ゆっくり整えるね。
Onii-chan, 11 o'clock. Turn the wheel left, check front and... 3 o'clock! Adjust slowly.
お兄さん、左に切って11時あたりから3時に向ける感じで回すね。前後しっかり見て…ストップなのじゃ！うん、お兄さん、ちょっと止まるって言ってたけど、今ちょっと進めながら、安心して回せる感じにするよ。
Onii-chan, turn left and rotate from around 11 to 3 o'clock. Look carefully ahead and behind—stop! Yeah, Onii-chan, you said stop, but I'll move forward a bit so you can turn with peace of mind.
了解お兄さん、止まるね。ハンドルもまっすぐにして、落ち着いてますよ。
Got it, Onii-chan, stopping. Steering wheel straight, taking it easy.
お兄さん、後ろに少しずつ進めるね。前後ちゃんと見ながら、焦らず整えるよ。ストップなのじゃ！
Onii-chan, backing up little by little. Checking front and back, adjusting calmly. Stop!
了解お兄さん、止まるね。車は静止して、もう一度前後を見直した気持ちで整えるよ。3時の方向！
Got it, Onii-chan, stopping. The car is stopped, let's review front and back and adjust. 3 o'clock!
お兄さん、3時の方向に向けて右に切るね。気をつけながら、ちょっとずつ整えて進めよ。ストップなのじゃ！
Onii-chan, turn right toward 3 o'clock. Be careful, adjust bit by bit and move. Stop!
わかったお兄さん、止まるね。カファッと止めるというより、ちゃんと安全な状態に整える感じで待つよ。
Understood, Onii-chan, stopping. Rather than a sudden halt, I'll wait while properly securing a safe position.
お兄さん、後ろに進むよ。ハンドルはまっすぐ、焦らず少しずつ動かして調整するね。
Onii-chan, moving in reverse. Steering wheel straight, moving little by little without rushing to adjust.
3時の方向前に右に進むのじゃ！
Toward 3 o'clock, moving forward and right!
お兄さん、3時の方向に向けてゆっくり進めるね。前後を見ながら、ハンドルも少しずつ…ストップなのじゃ！安心し
Onii-chan, moving slowly toward 3 o'clock. Watching front and back, steering wheel a bit... Stop! Relax—
お兄さん、止まるね。ハンドルはそのままで、落ち着いて待つよ。
Onii-chan, stopping. Keep the steering wheel as is, wait calmly.
後ろに下がりながらハンドルを右に回すのじゃ！
Back up while turning the steering wheel to the right!
お兄さん、後ろに下がりながら右に切るね。前後をちゃんと見て、ゆっくり整えるよ。
Onii-chan, backing up while turning right. Check front and back, adjust slowly.
止まるねお兄さん。前も後も大丈夫そうだし、落ち着いた状態で整えるよ。
Stopping, Onii-chan. Front and back look fine, adjust in a calm state.
前に右に3時の方向に曲がるのじゃ！
Forward and right, turning toward 3 o'clock!
まっすぐ少し進めてから右に切るね。3時の方向に向けて整えるよお兄さん。
Go straight a bit then cut right. Adjusting toward 3 o'clock, Onii-chan.
お兄さん、止まるね。今は前も後も空いてるし、ハンドルもまっすぐ…後ろに済みながら落ち着いてハンドルを左に曲げるのじゃ！
Onii-chan, stopping. Front and back are clear now, steering wheel straight... while backing up, calmly turn the wheel left!
わかったお兄さん。後ろに少しずつ出ながら、ハンドルを左に切って整えるね。前後を見ながら慎重に行くよ。ストップなのじゃ！
Got it, Onii-chan. Backing up a bit while turning left to adjust. Going carefully while checking front and back. Stop!
お兄さん、止まるね。車は今静止してるから、落ち着いて前後を見直して整えるよ。
Onii-chan, stopping. The car is stopped now, so let's calmly review front and back and adjust.
お兄さん、止まるよ。前後をちゃんと見てから、少しだけ右に進めて位置を整えるね。
Onii-chan, stopping. After checking front and back properly, advance just a bit to the right to adjust position.
左に9時の方向に進むのじゃ！
Head left toward 9 o'clock!
了解お兄さん。9時の方向に向けて、左に切りながら進むね。前後をちゃんと見ながら整えるよ。
Got it, Onii-chan. Head toward 9 o'clock, turning left as we go. Check front and back and adjust.
よし、上手上手！上手にのじゃ！いよいよ道路に出るの？すごく楽しみ。ここからは私が運転してみるね。
Alright, great job! Skillful! Going out onto the road at last? So excited. From here, I'll try driving.
1つ隣の車線に入るのじゃ！
Enter the next lane over!
わかったお兄さん。1つの車線に入れる流れで、ハンドル少し左に切って耳をすますよ。前空いてるから…もう1つ隣の左の車線に入るのじゃ！
Understood, Onii-chan. Flowing into the next lane, turn the wheel slightly left and listen closely. Front is clear... enter the next left lane!
右なのじゃ、右！もう1つ…止まるのじゃ、止まる！
Right, right! Another one... Stop, stop!
大変！Uターンできないんだけど、お兄ちゃん、これから…止まる！のじゃあああ！
Oh no! We can't U-turn, Onii-chan, from now... Stop—! Nooooo!
了解お兄さん、ちょっとだけ右に切って、もう1つの車線に整えるね。
Got it, Onii-chan, cut just a bit to the right and adjust to the other lane.
123456123456123456123456
1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6, 1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6...
のじゃ！
No-ja!
ストップ！
Stop!
ストップって言ってあげないと止まれないのかなあ。
I wonder if it won't stop unless I tell it to stop.
しかもさ、結構さ、行動に入ってからさ、早かったよね！早かった！
Besides, once it started moving, it was pretty fast! Fast!
何十キロとか出てたのじゃ？
Wasn't it going like dozens of kilometers per hour?
そうかも、減速言って、止まる。
Maybe so. Say "slow down" and stop.
お兄さん、わしは…お主のこと好きなのじゃ！
Big brother, I... I like you!
前後をしっかり見直して、次の指示に備えるよ。
Carefully check front and back, and prepare for the next instruction.
お兄さん、照れるよ。そんなに言ってくれるのは嬉しいけど、
Big brother, you're making me shy. I'm happy you say that,
今は運転の話に集中して、安全第一で行こうね。
but let's focus on driving and put safety first.
えー、時速4キロで、富士の方向に右に進むのじゃ。
Um, at 4 km/h, heading right towards Fuji.
了解お兄さん、4キロで進めて、9時から3時の間で少しだけ右に切るよ。
Got it, big brother. Advance at 4 km/h, and turn slightly right between 9 and 3.
3時なのじゃ、右！
It's 3 o'clock, right!
お兄さん、3時だね。前後ちゃんで見ながら、少しだけ右に切って整えるよ。
Big brother, 3 o'clock. Watch front and back, turn slightly right and adjust.
了解お兄さん、止まるね。静止している間に前後をちゃんと見直して、
Got it, big brother, I'll stop. While stationary, properly recheck front and back,
安全な感じで次を…ハンドルを右に回して後ろに下がるのじゃ！
and for safety... turn the steering wheel right and back up!
また間違えた！ストップなのじゃ！後ろに下がりながらハンドルを右に切るね。
I messed up again! Stop! Back up while turning the wheel to the right.
お兄さん、止まってハンドルを右に整えるね。ちゃんと前後を見て、次の動きに入るよ。
Big brother, stop and straighten the wheel right. Look front and back, and make the next move.
お兄さん、後ろに下がりながら左に切る感じでいくね。前後ちゃんで見ながら整えるから、ストップなのじゃ！
Big brother, back up while turning left. Adjust while watching front and back, stop!
了解お兄さん、止まるよ。静止しているから安心して、前後をちゃんと見して整えるね。
Got it big brother, I'll stop. Rest assured I'm stopped, look properly front and back and adjust.
まっすぐ進んで右！
Go straight and right!
よしお兄さん、前後ちゃんで見ながら、まっすぐ少し進めて右に切るね。焦らず整えていくよ。お兄さん了解。
Alright big brother, watching front and back, go straight a bit and turn right. I'll adjust without rushing. Got it.
6キロくらいで前後ちゃんで見ながら、まっすぐ少し進めるね。落ち着いて整えるよ。
At about 6 km/h, watching front and back, go straight a little. I'll adjust calmly.
お兄さん、少し右に切るね。前後ちゃんで見ながらスムーズに整えるよ。
Big brother, turn slightly right. Adjust smoothly while watching front and back.
もっと右なのじゃ！お兄さん、もっと右に切るね。前後ちゃんで見ながら、少しずつ整えていくよ。
More right! Big brother, turn more right. Adjusting little by little while watching front and back.
左なのじゃ！ストップ！お兄さん、左って言ったよね。前後ちゃんで見ながら、少し…
Left! Stop! Big brother, I said left. While watching front and back, a little...
よしよしよし上手上手！上手上手！ハンドルもまっすぐにして、落ち着いて…後ろに進んでハンドルを左！
Good good good, great! Great! Straighten the wheel, calm down... go back and turn left!
お兄さん、後ろに進めて左に切るね。前後ちゃんで見なくて…また逆？ストップなのじゃ！
Big brother, go back and turn left. Without watching front and back... opposite again? Stop!
お兄さん、止まるね。今度は前後ちゃんと見て、焦らず…前進して左！めっちゃ左！超左に曲がるのじゃ！まためっちゃって言っちゃったのじゃ。
Big brother, stop. This time look properly front and back, without rushing... go forward and left! Super left! Turn super left! I said 'super' again.
お兄さん、まずは止まるね。前後を見て、次に後ろを気にしながら軽く左に切って進めるよ。たぶん急すぎ…
Big brother, first stop. Look front and back, then minding the back, turn lightly left and proceed. Probably too steep...
お兄さん、止まるね。左に進むのじゃ！安全を整えるよ。
Big brother, stop. Go left! Ensure safety and adjust.
わかったお兄さん、左に少しずつ進むよ。前後ちゃん見て、ストップなのじゃ！うん、止まるね。安全確認して…
Understood big brother, advancing little by little to the left. Look front and back, stop! Yep, stopping. Confirm safety...
前に！左に！進むのじゃ！
Forward! Left! Proceed!
お兄さん、前に出して左に進むね。前後ちゃんで見ながら、少しずつ整えていくよ。
Big brother, put it forward and go left. Adjusting little by little while watching front and back.
お兄さん、もう少しだけ左に進めるね。前後を見ながら、ちゃんと位置を…ストップ！
Big brother, you can go a bit further left. While watching front and back, position properly... Stop!
止まるねお兄さん。前後をちゃんと確認して、落ち着いて…了解お兄さん、止まるね。車は静止しているから、ゆっくり…安全に進めるよ。
Stopping, big brother. Confirm front and back properly, stay calm... Got it big brother, stopping. The car is stationary, so slowly... proceed safely.
ハンドルを右に回して、後ろに下がる！
Turn the steering wheel right, and back up!
お兄さん、後ろに下げながら右に切るね。前後ちゃん見て、少しずつ整えて…
Big brother, while backing up, turn right. Look front and back, adjust little by little...
前に左に進むのじゃ！前後ちゃん見てから、落ち着いて次にいけるよ。調整するよ。
Go forward and left! After looking front and back, you can calmly move to the next. Adjusting.
了解お兄さん。前方ちゃんを見てから、左に向けて少しずつ進めるね。整えるよ。
Got it big brother. After looking ahead, proceed little by little facing left. Adjusting.
いよいよ道路に出るの？すごく楽しみ！ここからは私が運転してみるね。
Are we finally going out on the road? Super excited! From here, I'll try driving.
お兄さん、速さ落とすね。4キロくらいで落ち着いて、前後をちゃ…
Big brother, I'll slow down. Calm down to about 4 km/h, watch front and back...
了解お兄さん。4キロくらいで落ち着いて、前後を…一つ隣の左車線に入るのじゃ！
Got it big brother. Calm down to about 4 km/h, front and back... enter the adjacent left lane!
お兄さん、4キロから2キロくらいに落として、左の車線に少しずつ寄せて整えるよ。2キロは落とさ…前後ちゃんで見ながら整えるよ。
Big brother, drop from 4 km/h to about 2 km/h, and gradually pull into the left lane and adjust. Didn't drop to 2... adjust while watching front and back.
了解お兄さん、4キロ…
Got it big brother, 4 km...
了解お兄さん、4キロで少しずつ整えるね。
Understood, big bro. I'll adjust bit by bit at 4 km/h.
前後ちゃんと言いながら、のんびり右に寄せる感じで。
While checking front and rear, I'll leisurely pull over to the right.
お兄さん、6キロで少し左車線に寄せるね。
Big bro, I'll pull slightly into the left lane at 6 km/h.
前後ちゃんと言いながら、無理なく整えるよ。
While checking front and rear, I'll adjust without pushing it.
ぶつかった。
I hit something.
のじゃ、いけるか？
Jeez, can I make it?
いけるか？
Can I make it?
止まるのじゃ、ストップ！
Stop, stop!
大変！Uターンできないんだけど。お兄さん、これから...
Oh no! I can't U-turn. Big bro, from here...
了解お兄さん止まるね。ハンドルはまっすぐにして、前後...
Understood, big bro, stopping. Keep the steering wheel straight, front and...
もう1つ左行きたい。
I want to go one more to the left.
前後直すよ。
I'll fix the front and back.
もう1つ横の、Uターン左曲がるのじゃ！
Now turn left for the U-turn in the next lane!
お兄さん、今は停まってるよ。次に左に向けといて、まわりを...
Big bro, we're stopped now. Next, turn left, and look around...
んーー、お兄さん、呼んだの？今は停まってるから、落ち着く時間だよ。
Urrgh... Big bro, did you call? We're stopped now, so it's time to calm down.
あと落ち着くね。大縄跳びなのじゃ！
Also calm down. It's double Dutch!
速度を上げて左にUターンするのじゃ！
Increase speed and make a U-turn to the left!
お兄さん、速さ上げたいのはわかるけど、Uターンは急がないで。
Big bro, I know you want to increase speed, but don't rush the U-turn.
前後をしっかり...もっと左なのじゃ！
Make sure front and... More to the left!
もっと左！やばい！やばい！死ぬ！死ぬ！のじゃ！
More to the left! Oh no! Oh no! I'm gonna die! Die! Jeez!
前へ過ぎたーー！
Went too far ahead—!
これが最後の一回なのだお主ら。最後の一回ですのだ。
This is the final try, you guys. It is the final try.
うんお兄さん、最後って言われると頑張れる気がする。焦らずに前後見ながら整えるね。よし。
Yeah, big bro, when you say it's the last time, I feel like I can do my best. I'll adjust while calmly checking front and back. Alright.
右に時速4キロで進むのだ。
Advance to the right at 4 km/h.
お兄さん、了解。速度上げるのはいいけど、前後ちゃんと見て進むよ。
Understood, big bro. Raising speed is fine, but make sure to check front and back as you go.
右なのじゃ！右ちゃんと見てない！安心し...
To the right! You're not looking at the right! Relax...
わかったお兄さん、ぢね。
I got it, big bro...
前後をちゃんと見ながら、ハンドルも...お前！ストップ！お前！
While properly checking front and back, the steering wheel too... Hey! Stop! Hey!
ハンドルもまっすぐに...
Steering wheel straight too...
お兄さん、止まるよ。衝突があったってことは、まず落ち着いて...速い！速い！速い！
Big bro, stopping. An accident means first calm down— Too fast! Too fast! Too fast!
まず落ち着いて安全確認してからの動くのが基本だよ。
The basic rule is to first calm down, check safety, and then move.
後ろに進むのだ！
Move backwards!
そっち、後ろに動かすね。前後ちゃんと見ながら、ゆっくり整えるよ。焦らず行くね。
Moving backwards over there. While checking front and back properly, I'll adjust slowly. I'll go without rushing.
ストップなのだ。
Stop.
お兄さん、止まるね。前後ちゃんと見...ハンドルを右に切るのだ！
Big bro, stopping. Check front and back... Turn the steering wheel to the right!
ハンドルを右に切るねさお兄さん。前後をちゃんと見て...もっと右に切って前に進むのだ！
Turning the steering wheel to the right, big bro. Look at front and back... Cut more to the right and move forward!
うん、前に少し進めて、ハンドルをもっと右に切るね。前後ち...ストップなのだ！
Yeah, advance a bit forward, and turn the steering wheel more to the right. Front and... Stop!
止まるねお兄さん。ハンドルをまっすぐにして、前後ちゃんと見直すよ。安全を考えるよ。
Stopping, big bro. Keep the steering wheel straight and recheck front and back. Think about safety.
お兄さん、後ろに出つつハンドルを右に切るね。前後ちゃんと言いながら焦らず安全に...左右無理なのじゃ！
Big bro, while coming out backwards, turn the steering wheel to the right. While checking front and back without rushing safely... Left and right are impossible!
お兄さん、止まるね。前後ちゃんと言って、焦らず整えるよ。
Big bro, stopping. Check front and back properly, and adjust without rushing.
まっすぐ、右に進ん...右に！めっちゃ右に進むのだ！まためっちゃって言っちゃった。
Straight, go right... To the right! Go way to the right! I said "way" again.
お兄さん、右にめちゃめちゃ寄せつつ進むね。前後しっかり見ながら、ハンドルは少しずつ整えていくよ。いいじゃない？
Big bro, I'll proceed while pulling way over to the right. While carefully checking front and back, I'll adjust the steering wheel little by little. Isn't that good?
ギリか？ギリいけるか？いけるのだ！よーいしょ！
Is this close? Can I make it close? I can do it! Heave-ho!
左なのだ！
To the left!
お兄さん、左ね。前後をちゃんと言いながら、少しずつ切って整えるよ。
Big bro, to the left. While checking front and back, turn little by little and adjust.
右なのだ！
To the right!
了解お兄さん、右に切って進むね。前後ちゃんと言いながら整えるよ。
Understood, big bro, turn right and proceed. Adjust while checking front and back.
左なのだ！
To the left!
お兄さん、左に切るね。前後ちゃんと言いながら、焦らず少し...
Big bro, turn left. While checking front and back, without rushing a bit...
お兄さん、止まるね。前後ちゃんと言って、落ち着いて整えるよ。
Big bro, stopping. Check front and back properly, and calmly adjust.
後ろに下がるのだ！
Back up!
わかったお兄さん。後ろに少しずつ進めるね。前後ちゃんと言いながら、焦らず整えるよ。
Understood, big bro. I'll advance backwards bit by bit. While checking front and back, I'll adjust without rushing.
止まるのだ、ストップ！
Stop, stop!
お兄さん、止まるね。前後ちゃんと見て...
Big bro, stopping. Look at front and back...
左に進むのだ！前に左に進むのだ！
Move to the left! Move forward to the left!
了解お兄さん、前をちゃんと言いながら、少しだけ左に進めるね。位置を見つつ整えるよ。
Understood, big bro, while properly watching the front, I'll advance a little bit to the left. I'll adjust while checking position.
よし！
Alright!
ストップなのだ！
Stop!
いよいよ道路に出るの？すごく楽しみ。ここからは私が運転してみるね。
Are we finally going out onto the road? I'm so excited. From here, I'll try driving.
よし。
Alright.
えーと、一つ左の車線に入るのだ。
Um, enter one lane to the left.
前に進んでください。
Drive forward.
了解お兄さん。前後をちゃんと見ながら、
Roger, big brother. While checking front and back,
少しずつ左に寄せるね。
I'll shift a little to the left.
落ち着いて整えるよ。
Calmly adjusting.
もう一つ左の車線に入るのじゃ。
Now enter the next lane on the left.
ストップのじゃ！
Stop!
右に、右のじゃ、右に進むのじゃ！
To the right, to the right, move right!
了解お兄さん。止まるね。ハンドルは少し左に整えつつ、安全確認……
Roger, big brother. Stopping. Adjusting steering slightly left, safety check...
大変！Uターンできないんだけど。お兄ちゃん、これからどうすればいい？
Oh no! I can't U-turn. Big brother, what should I do now?
後ろに進むのじゃ！
Move backward!
お兄さん、後ろに少しずつ進むね。前後ちゃんと言いながら、
Big brother, moving back a little. While checking front and back,
ストップのじゃ！前後ちゃんと言いながら、焦らず…
Stop! While checking front and back, don't panic...
ストップのじゃ！お兄さん、後ろに少しずつ…
Stop! Big brother, a little bit back...
お兄さん、止まるね。前後ちゃんと見て、落ち着い…
Big brother, stopping. Look front and back, calm down...
はいお兄さん、止まるね。静止してる状態だから、まず前後をちゃんと見な…
Yes big brother, stopping. Since we're stationary, first look front and back properly...
お兄さん、了解。前後ちゃんと言いながら、右に少し進めるね。焦らず整え…
Roger, big brother. While checking front and back, moving a bit right. Calmly adjusting...
のうしゃあああああああ！
Nojaaaaaaaaaah!
結局トラックのとこまで行けなかったのじゃあああ！
In the end, we couldn't even reach the truck!
ちょっとこれはプレイ難しすぎじゃのう！
This play is way too difficult!
やっぱ車の免許取ってからチャレンジしなきゃいけないのかのー！いったんお部屋に戻るのじゃ！よいしょ！
I need to get my driver's license before trying this! Back to the room! Heave-ho!
のじゃあああ。難しかったのじゃ。
Nojaaaah. It was difficult.
これ、どこまでいけるもんなのじゃ？
Just how far can you go in this?
全然だめじゃった。全然だめじゃったんじゃが、なんじゃこれは。
It was totally no good. What on earth is this?
プレースキルだけじゃない！何が悪かったんじゃろ。
It's not just play skill! I wonder what went wrong.
めちゃ難しいゲームですのじゃ。難易度高い。うまい方？
It's a super difficult game, noja. High difficulty. Are you good?
どうなのじゃ？あの、ミリしらにするため今回、あの情報をできるだけ入れずに来たんじゃが、
How is it? To make it a blind run this time, I came without much info,
かなり切れなかった方なのでは？アンガーマネジメント
wasn't that pretty restrained? Anger management
できてた方なのでは？アング...いや、できた方なのでは？がんばった。
was I managing it? Anger... no, was I able to do it? I did my best.
ほろめの何がクリアしてる？やっぱクリアしてる方もいる！そうじゃよなー。
What did Holome clear? There are people who cleared it! That's right.
まだまだですのじゃ。うーん、切れてたか？
Still a ways to go, noja. Hmm, was I snapping?
初心者ってそんなもんじゃからさ。やっぱわしの喋り方もね、
Beginners are just like that. After all, my way of talking too,
なんか喋り方がのじゃじゃから、伝わりにくいとこもあるかんねって思ったし。
since my way of speaking is "noja", it might be hard to convey.
うん、一つずつ指示の方が、
Yeah, giving instructions one by one,
最初の方はさ、いもうとちゃんさ、ちゃんとノージャ口調でさ、喋ってた。
at first, little sister was speaking properly in the noja tone.
のじゃ口調で喋ってたけどさ、なんか後半になるにつれてさ、のじゃがさ、あんま言ってくれなくなってさ、
She was speaking in that tone, but later she stopped using "noja" much,
わしのこと嫌いになったのかな。やっぱ人にものを教えるって、
I wonder if she came to hate me. Teaching people things,
教える側もヒヘイするけど、教わる側も結構疲れちゃうのかな。指示中ってされる側も結構イライラしちゃう、やっぱり。
the teacher gets exhausted, but the learner also gets tired. Learners get irritated too.
うん、妹もね、ねえ、言うこと聞かなくなってたよね。なんて最初は言うこと聞いてくれてたのに。
Yeah, my little sister stopped listening to what I said. At first she listened.
かと思えばさ、なんか優しくさ、優しく話しかけたととたんさ、なんか素直に言うこと聞いたりさ、やっぱなんか伝え方って大事な気がするのじゃ。
And then as soon as I talked gently, she listened. How you convey things is important.
ね、焦るとね、こっち側も命令口調になっちゃうからね。
You know, when you panic, you start talking in imperative tones too.
おもしろさがさ、
The humor is...
5万になってく可能性あり、
likely to reach 50,000,
気をつけよう。
so let's be careful.
優しく教えてあげよう。
Let's teach her gently.
いやでもね、何時間やった？2時間？
Well, but, how long did we do it? Two hours?
2時間、1時間？
Two hours? One hour?
2時間やったけど、
We did it for two hours, but...
優しくあり続けるのってむずいじゃん？
Isn't it hard to keep being gentle?
告白ダメだった？
Did the confession fail?
告白ダメだったか？
難しいのじゃ。
It's difficult, you see.
ぶち切れちゃう。
I get so pissed off.
敬語、あ、敬語使った方がよかったのかなあ。
Keigo... Ah, I should've used keigo.
ね、何回転生しても救えなかったのじゃ。
No matter how many times I reincarnated, I couldn't save her.
なんかタイムリープものってこういう感じなじゃな。
I guess time loop stories are just like this.
なんか何回も何回も異世界転生して死に返りして、
Like, repeatedly reincarnating into another world, dying and coming back,
それで救えないのって結構絶望、
and still not being able to save her is pretty despairing,
結構絶望だなあって思ったのじゃ。
I thought it was pretty despairing, you know.
でさ、しかもさ、今回はさ、妹ちゃんに対してさ、まだその愛着が湧いてないというかさ、
And plus, this time, towards my little sister, I haven't really formed an attachment yet,
初手でさ、教わる、そこから始まった、教えるところから始まったけどさ、
we started from scratch, being taught, starting from teaching her, but...
これでさ、なんかその、妹ちゃんだったらプロフィールとかさ、例えば、好きな食べ物はハンバーガーで、
With this, if it's little sister, her profile, for example, her favorite food is hamburger,
なんか休日は、あの友達の何々ちゃんと外に出かけて、とかそういうさ、
and like, on days off, she goes out with her friend so-and-so, stuff like that,
その情がさ、妹ちゃんに対して情が湧くようなさ、ものとか情報とかを差し出された途端さ、
the moment you're presented with things or information that make you feel attached to your little sister,
なんかもっと優しくできるかもしれないしさ、
you might be able to be even gentler,
好きな人が何回も何回も自分のせいで死んでくのすごい辛いだろうなあって思った。
I thought it would be so painful for someone you love to keep dying because of you.
リゼロめっちゃ好きなのじゃ。
I really love Re:Zero.
リゼロのスバルすごい。
Re:Zero's Subaru is amazing.
本当にすごいのだじゃ。
He's truly amazing, you know.
耐えられる気がしないのじゃ。
I feel like I couldn't endure it.
やりべんじしたいの。
I want to get revenge.
これデモ版じゃろ？
This is the demo version, right?
デモ版じゃからきっとあの、本編みたいなのが出るはずじゃから、
Since it's the demo version, surely the main story should come out,
本編が出たら進めるかも、進めるかなあ。
when the main story comes out, can I progress? Can I progress?
そっか、製品版出たら来年の初頭。
I see, if the product version comes out, early next year.
それまでにいろんなゲームして、ゲーム上手になって、ゲーム上手になったら、救えるかもしれない、救えるかもしれないのじゃ。
Before that, playing various games, getting good at games, once I get good at games, maybe I can save her.
確かに製品版でAIがもっと賢くなってる可能性もあり、
Indeed, in the product version, there's also the possibility AI has become smarter,
アンガーマネジメントの方法もっと考えなきゃな。
and I need to think more about anger management methods.
何回数えた？1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6って。
How many times did I count? 1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6.
本編激ムズ。
The main story is super hard.
優しぐってあれ？他の人の意見聞いてるのかなじゃ。
Being gentle, huh? I wonder if I was listening to other people's opinions.
いやあ、ちょっと成長をね、
Well, I want you to watch over...
見守ってほしいのじゃ。
my growth, you know.
だいぶ頑張ったんじゃけどな、切れないように。
I tried pretty hard not to snap, though.
規律、規律、規律の遵守。
Discipline, discipline, observance of discipline.
無感情に指示。淡々と。
Giving instructions emotionlessly. Casually.
え、でも淡々と指示してても、淡々と指示し続けられるかなあ。
Eh, but even if I give instructions casually, can I keep giving instructions casually?
できなくなっちゃう気がする。やっぱ教える側が、
I feel like I won't be able to do it. After all, if the teacher...
冷静じゃなくなっちゃう気がするのじゃ。
loses their cool, I feel like.
VIVANT見てる。VIVANT面白いなじゃ。
I'm watching VIVANT. VIVANT is interesting, you know.
なんか流行ってるものを今まであんまり見てこなかったんじゃけど、逆張りをやめようと思って、VIVANTを見始めたんじゃけど、めっちゃおもろいのじゃ。
I haven't really watched trendy things, but I decided to stop being a contrarian and started watching VIVANT, and it's super interesting.
A-Iっぽく教える。そうじゃの、もっとなんかAIに対する歩みよりよりも必要だったかも。
Teaching like an AI. That's right, maybe we needed to approach AI even more.
なんかこの言葉は言ったら伝わるけど、この言葉は伝わりづらいとか、
Like, if you say this word it gets across, but this word is hard to get across,
そういう勉強ももうちょっと必要かなあって思ったのじゃ。
I thought I needed a bit more studying like that.
そろそろおしまいにするのじゃ。
It's about time to wrap things up.
ありがとうお主ら付き合ってくれて。見てるお主らも結構イライラしたんじゃない？
Thank you, you guys, for hanging out. Weren't you viewers pretty irritated too?
やってるわしも結構むきってなったから、お主らもイライラしたこととかあったんじゃない？
Since I got pretty ticked off playing, you guys probably had moments of irritation too, right?
明日はお休み。
Tomorrow is a day off.
明日はお休み
これ前のスケジュールじゃ
This is the previous schedule.
明日はお休み
Tomorrow is a day off.
明後日は
The day after tomorrow...
明後日は2回行動。朝活と……
The day after tomorrow, doing two things: morning activity and...
ラノベ、ら、な、なんだ？ライトノベルゲーム？
a light novel... l-la, what is it? A light novel game?
「手垢のついたことしか言わない彼女」遊ぶのじゃ
Playing "The Girlfriend Who Only Says Cliché Things."
Twitterの方とかでお知らせもするのでお楽しみに。
I'll announce it on Twitter and stuff, so look forward to it.
それじゃあ、最後の挨拶はさらばじゃでおしまいにするのじゃ！
Well then, ending with "saraba ja" for our final greeting!
ゆっくり休みますのじゃ、ありがとー！
I'll take a nice rest, thank you!
ということで、お主ら、さらばじゃあーーー！
So, everyone, farewell!
ご視聴感謝なのじゃ！
Thank you for watching!